字幕翻译&校对：william2568 索唱 Cool 影片注释：四七酱 索唱 Boxer
- william2568 出品 -
世界真的是大变样了
Things are never gonna be the same now.
你看看这幅画 画中有外星人
I mean, look at this. We got aliens.
还有这个绿色的大家伙 拆毁了不少大楼
We got big, green guys tearing down buildings.
我小的时候画的还是牛仔和印第安人
When I was a kid I used to draw cowboys and Indians.
应该把他们叫做"美洲土著居民" 但是...
Actually, it's Native American, but...
嗯 不管怎么说 画的还可以吧
Yeah, tell you what, though... Not bad, is it?
是啊 还行 这孩子挺有前途的
No, yeah. Kid's got a future.
嗯..
Yeah, well...
也许吧
We'll see, I guess.
嘿 你这样是锯不开那玩意的
No, hey... You can't saw through that stuff.
这些外星垃圾很难搞的 你要用他们用的工具
These alien bastards are tough. You gotta use the stuff they use.
- 看到了没 就这样搞 - 明白了
See? All right.
这都下午了 可算把你盼来了
Glad you could join us. Afternoon.
- 我的闹钟没响 - 是啊 是啊 你闹钟的问题
- My alarm's been going off... - Yeah, yeah, yeah. Your alarm.
听着 按我说的那样 把那些装甲堆起来就好
Look, just go stock that armor plating like I asked.
这可是很大的一单生意
This is a huge deal for us.
请注意 根据行政令396-B
Attention, please. In accordance with Executive order 396-B...
所有的战后清理行动现在由我们负责
All post battle cleanup operations are now under our jurisdiction.
多谢你们的劳动 从今以后这就归我们管了
Thank you for your service. We'll take it from here.
- 你是谁啊? - 我们是有资格的处理人员
- Who the hell are you? - Qualified personnel.
听着 我是签了合同的 负责清理城市里的这些玩意 我和市政府签了合同的
Look, I have a city contract, to salvage all this, okay? With the city, so...
抱歉 图姆斯先生 但是现在所有的城市清理工作都由我们负责了
I apologize, Mr. Toomes. But all salvage operations are now under our jurisdiction.
请交出你们所有收集的外星材料
Please turn over any and all exotic materials that you've collected,
- 否则你会受到起诉 - 女士 你...
- or you will be prosecuted. - Ma'am, what are....
请等一下
Please, wait up, come on.
听我说
Look...
为了干这活我买了卡车
I bought trucks for this job.
还雇了一伙人 他们都要养家糊口
I've brought in a whole new crew. These guys have families.
我也要养活自己的家人 我已经在这上面投入了一切
I have a family. I'm all in on this.
- 我不能就这么丢了房子 - 很抱歉 先生 对此我无能为力
- I can't lose my house! - I'm sorry, sir. There's nothing I can do.
下次 别这么不自量力了
Maybe next time, don't overextend yourself.
你说什么？
What'd you say?
是啊 他说得对 我是不自量力
Yeah. He's right. I overextended myself.
把枪放下
Put them down.
如果你有什么意见 可以去找我的上级
If you have a grievance, you may take it up with my superiors.
你的上级？你他妈的上级是谁啊？
Your superiors? Who the hell are they?!
史塔克工业与联邦政府共同建立的合资企业
The joint venture between Stark Industries and the federal government,
灾害控制部
the Department of Damage Control,
将会监督 外星及其它特殊材料的收集与存储过程
will oversee the collection and storage of alien and other exotic materials.
所以现在政府让这个搞出烂摊子的混蛋来收拾残局 还付钱给他?
So now the assholes who made this mess are getting paid to clean it up?
- 是啊 都被他操纵了 - 专家估计 有超过1500吨的
- Yeah, it's all rigged. - Experts estimate there are over
外星材料分布在三州地区
1,500 tons of exotic materials scattered throughout the Tristate area.
头儿 我这还有一车昨天留下的东西
Hey, Chief, we still have another load from yesterday.
- 我们是不是应该把这些上交？ - 我是不打算搬过去了
- We're supposed to turn this in, right? - I ain't hauling it.
真是太可惜了 咱可以用这些外星垃圾造很多不错的玩意
It's too bad. We could've made some pretty cool stuff from all that alien junk.
要我说 就把它们留下来吧
I tell you what. Let's keep it.
世界在改变
The world's changing.
我们也是时候改变了
It's time we change, too.
八年后
成功了 梅森
Here you go, Mason.
生意很不错
Business is good.
导演：彼得・帕克
a Film by Peter Parker
纽约 皇后区
New York, Queens.
这个街区治安不好 但那是我的家
纽约 皇后区
It's a rough borough, but hey, it's home.
New York, Queens.
这个街区治安不好 但那是我的家
It's a rough borough, but hey, it's home.
- 你在跟谁说话？ - 没呢
- Who are you talking to? - No one.
- 只是录一些这次旅行的短视频 - 你应该知道 你不能把它给别人看吧
- Just making a little video of the trip. - You know you can't show it to anyone.
- 我知道的 - 那你为什么还要给视频作解说呢
- Yeah, I know. - Then why are you narrating in that voice?
- 因为这挺有意思的 - "挺有意思"
- Hmm. Because it's fun. - "Fun".
为什么他们都叫你"哈皮"呢
So, uhh, why do they call you "Happy"?
快点 我不会帮你扛包的 我们走
Come on. I'm not carrying your bags. Let's go.
嘿 坐飞机前我是不是得先上个厕所
Hey, should I go to the bathroom before?
- 飞机上有厕所 - 哇 无人驾驶？这么酷啊
- There's a bathroom on it. - Woah, no pilot? That's awesome!
- 你就打算坐这么？ - 对
- Is that where you're gonna sit? - Yeah.
- 你这是第一次坐私人飞机么 - 这是我第一次坐飞机
- Is it your first time on a private plane? - It's my first time on any plane.
这个声音正常么？
Should it be making that noise?
其实现在还没人跟我说清楚 为什么要我来柏林 要我来干什么
No one has actually told me why I'm in Berlin. Or what I'm doing.
好像是什么 美国队长发疯了
Something about, Captain America going crazy...
- 你住这间 - 你住我隔壁啊?
- This is you. - Oh, we're neighbors?
我们不住一起 去把装备穿上
We're not roommates. Suit up.
- 放松 彼得 你能搞定的 - 你这是穿的啥呢？
- Okay, Peter. You got this. - What the hell are you wearing?
- 我的装备啊 - 那个箱子呢？
- It's my suit. - Where's the case?
什么箱子？
What case?
这不是我...我还以为这是个衣橱呢 那边也是我的房间么
That's not my-- what? I thought that was a closet. This is still my room?
我的房间比我想象的要大...
My room is way bigger than I...
我找到他说的那个箱子了
Hey, I found the case.
"一点小升级"?
"A minor upgrade"?
哇 我的天
Woah! Oh, my God!
穿上啊
Put it on.
这是我见过的 最酷的东西！
This is the coolest thing I've ever seen, ever!
- 动作快点 - 我不明白...这是给我的么？
- Let's go! - But, I don't understand, is--- is it for me?
哈皮 哈皮 等等我
Happy, Happy, wait!
这简直太疯狂了！太疯狂了！看看这玩意！看看这眼睛！
This is insane! Insane! Look at this thing! Look at the eyes!
- 这是我人生中最棒的一天 - 快走吧
- This is the greatest day of my life. - Let's go.
那里是 美国队长 钢铁侠 黑寡妇
Okay. There's Captain America, Iron Man, Black Widow...
- 哇 那个新人是谁？ - 小蜘蛛！
- Woah, who's that new guy? - Underoos!
叫我了 我要走了 我要上场了
That's me! I gotta go, I gotta go!
嘿 各位
Hey, everyone.
刚刚的事简直太疯狂了 我和美国队长打起来了
Okay, so the craziest thing just happened, right? I just had a fight with Captain America and I stole his shield,
我偷了他的盾牌 然后把它扔向了他 什么情况..
and I threw it at him, and I... What the hell...
他变大了 我要走了 待会继续
He's big now! I gotta go. Hang on.
刚刚发生的事简直太惊人了 史塔克先生叫道"嘿 小蜘蛛"
It was, the most amazing thing that's ever happened. So Mr. Stark's like: "Hey, Underoos!"
我就一个跟头翻过去 把美国队长的盾给偷了
And I just sort of flipped in, and I stole Cap's shield,
然后我就说 "嘿 大家好啊"
and I was like, "Hey, what's up, everybody?"
等一下 来了
Hey, just a second. Coming.
- 嘿 - 这里的墙不隔音
- Hey! - We have thin walls here.
- 你在干什么 做视频日记么  - 对
- What are you doing, a little video diary? - Yeah.
- 好吧 - 我跟他说过不要录 但他还是一直在录
- It's alright. - I told him not to do it. He was filming everything.
嘿
Hey, hey, hey...
其实我们也应该给你姨妈录一个证明你不在场的视频
You know what, we should make an alibi video for your aunt, anyway.
准备好了么
You ready?
钢铁侠的淤青是《美国队长3：内战》中所留 已有明显愈合
靠近点 我们俩都上镜
Okay. Get in the frame.
嘿 梅 在忙什么 你穿的是什么呢 这么暴露
Hey, May. How are you doing? What are you wearing? Something skimpy, I hope.
彼得 之前这段不太合适 再来一次 把前面的删掉
Peter, that's inappropriate. Let's start over. We can edit it.
三二一 开始 嘿 梅 我的天..
3, 2, 1. Hey, May! My gosh...
就是想告诉你 你的外甥周末
Wanted to tell you what an incredible job your nephew did...
在史塔克工业实习 表现出色
this weekend at the Stark Internship retreat.
- 给大家留下了深刻影响 - 我靠
- Everyone was impressed. - Come on!
- 刚刚经过了个岔道 抱歉 - 因为你没走皇后大道 所以才有这么多情况
- It's a friggin' merge, I'm sorry. - This, 'cause you're not on Queens Boulevard.
哈皮的梦想就是当上资产管理人
See, Happy is hoping to get bumped up to Asset Management.
他原来是安保人员 再之前 当过一段时间的司机
He was forehead of security. And before that, he was just a driver.
那是我们之间的私人谈话
That was a private conversation.
我不喜欢拿这个开玩笑 我考虑了很久才告诉你的...
I don't like joking about this. It was hard for me to talk to you about that...
- 说真的 他在飞机上打呼噜了么 - 好了 我们到了...
- No seriously, was he snoring aboard the plane? - Okay, here we go...
- 哈皮 能让我们单独待一会么 - 你想让我下车？
- Happy, can you give us a moment? - You want me to leave the car?
我想让你去把彼得的东西从行李箱内拿出来
I want you to grab Peter's case out of the trunk.
我能留着那套装备？
I can keep the suit?
是啊 我刚刚才跟你说的
Yes, we were just talking about it.
我跟你说
Do me a favor, though...
哈皮就算你的联系人了 别让他太紧张
Happy's kinda your point guy in this. Don't stress him out.
别做什么傻事 我看过他的心电图
Don't do anything stupid. I've seen his cardiogram.
- 好么 - 好
- All right? - Yes.
别做什么我会去做的事 当然 我不做的事你千万别做
Don't do anything I would do. And definitely don't do anything I wouldn't do.
你所做的那些事处于灰色地带
There's a little gray area in there and that's where you operate.
- 等下 是不是我这就加入了复仇者联盟？ - 不是
- Wait, does that mean that I'm an Avenger? - No.
- 他住几楼？ - 七楼
- He's at? - Seventh floor.
- 我能自己拿上去 不用麻烦你了 - 你要自己拿上去么
- I can take that up. You don't have to take it. - You're gonna take it?
- 嗯 我自己拿 - 谢谢你
- Yeah. I can take that. - Thank you.
- 所以 我下一次"实习"是什么时候 你懂的 - 什么?你说的是下次任务么
- So, when's our next, "retreat", you know? - What? Next mission?
- 是的 任务 任务 - 我会联系你的
- Yeah, the mission, the mission. - We'll call you.
- 那你有我的电话号码么 - 不 我的意思是 我们会联系你
- Well did you have my number? - No, I mean we'll call you.
就像其他人打电话给你 也是联系你 明白了吧
Like, someone will call you. Alright?
这不是拥抱 我只是帮你打开车门
That's not a hug, I'm just grabbing the door for you.
我们的关系 还没到那么亲密呢
We're not--- we're not there yet.
再见！
Bye!
彼得T恤图案是《生活大爆炸》中 桌游"理论物理实验室"的游戏标语
他们会联系我的
They're gonna call me.
两个月后
2 MONTHS LATER
嘿 哈皮 我就发短信跟你聊聊 我的放学时间是14:45
Hey, Happy. Just write for fun. I'm finished school on 14:45.
准备好参加下次任务啦 顺便说一句 我是彼得・帕克
Ready for next mission! This Peter, BTW. Parker
你好啊
What's up, Penis Parker?
- 市科技中学的同学们 大家早上好  - 大家别忘记带校友返校日活动的门票哟
- Rise and shine, Midtown Science and Technology. - Students, don't forget about your homecoming tickets.
- 你有约好一起参加活动的人么？ - 谢谢 杰森 我已经有伴了
- Do you have a date for homecoming? - Thanks, Jason, but I already have a date.
- 好吧 - 嗯
- Okay. - Yep.
←钢铁侠的父亲
霍华德・史塔克
你马上来我的办公室
You, in my office, right now!
加入我吧 咱们一起 用乐高积木搭一个新的死星模型吧
Join me, and together, we'll build my new Lego Death Star.
- 你说什么？ - 真蹩脚
- What?! - So lame.
不会吧 这么牛 总共要多少块积木？
No way, that's awesome! How many pieces?
3803块
3,803.
- 真是太疯狂了 -是的
- That's insane. - I know!
- 我们今晚一起搭么？ - 今晚没空啊 我要去史塔克工业实习
- You wanna build it tonight? - I can't tonight. I got the Stark internship.
- 去实习啊 - 是啊 没错
- Stark internship. - Yeah, exactly.
- 哥们 你都找到实习了 - 不久后 还有希望转为正式工作呢
- Boy's got that internship. - Hopefully, soon it'll lead to a real job.
那是很棒 你的老板会这么说
That would be so sweet. He'd be all,
"彼得 表格做的不错 这是给你的金币"
"Good job on those spreadsheets, Peter. Here's a gold coin."
- 开个玩笑 我不知道你做的是什么工作 - 我干的就是你说的那些活
- I don't know how jobs work. - That's exactly how they work.
我在家先把死星的基本框架搭好 然后再去找你
I'll knock out the basic bones of the Death Star at my place, and then I'll come by afterwards.
因为一般情况下 框架是最难拼的
Because for the most part, the difficult thing will be just the base of it.
最上面的部分肯定...
The top half will....
那就这么定了
That'd be great.
好 那么我们要怎么计算从A点到B点的加速度
Okay, so how do we calculate linear acceleration between points A and B?
请讲
Flash.
重力乘上夹角的正弦值 除以质量
It's the product of sine of the angle and gravity, divided by the mass.
回答错误 彼得
Nope. Peter.
你在听课么
Are you still with us?
墙上画像最右端是"绿巨人"布鲁斯・班纳博士
在的 在的
Uh, yeah. Yeah. Uhh...
抵消质量 用重力乘上夹角的正弦值就可以了
Mass cancels out, so it's just gravity times sine.
正确 你看 回答的最快
Right. See, Flash? Being the fastest
不一定是最好的 因为可能会答错
isn't always the best if you are wrong.
你完蛋了
You're dead.
今天我们来谈谈丹麦物理学家尼尔斯・玻尔
Today we're gonna be talking about Danish physicist Neils Bohr.
相信我 他所提出的量子理论并不是你们想象中的那么无聊
But trust me, there's nothing "Bohr-ing" about his discoveries regarding quantum theory.
丽兹穿的是新上衣么
Did Liz get a new top?
不 以前她就穿过这件的 但是
No. We've seen that before, but...
- 从来没搭配过那条短裙 - 丽兹
- never with that skirt. - Liz!
嘿 看起来很不错
Hey! That looks so good.
咱们别一直盯着人家看了 挺诡异的
We should probably stop staring before it gets creepy, though.
我早就注意到你们两个潘坷
Too late. You guys are losers.
- 那你为啥还坐在那边呢 - 因为我没朋友啊
- Then why do you sit with us? - 'Cause I don't have any friends.
下一个问题 最重的天然元素是什么
Let's move to the next question: What is the heaviest naturally occuring element?
氢是最轻的 不对 你问的不是这个
Hydrogen's the lightest. That's not the question. Ok.
- 铀 - 回答正确 亚伯拉罕
- Uranium. - That is correct. Thank you, Abraham.
请打开课本 翻到第十页
Please open your books to page 10.
彼得 这可是一次集体活动
Peter, it's nationals. Is there no way
你就请周末两天的假不行么
you could take one weekend off?
我不能去华盛顿 因为史塔克先生需要我
I can't go to Washington because if Mr. Stark needs me,
- 我得保证他能在这找到我 - 你甚至都没见过托尼・史塔克本人
- then I have to make sure I'm here. - You've never even been in the same room as Tony Stark.
- 等等 什么情况 - 彼得不去华盛顿了
- Wait, what's happening? - Peter's not going to Washington.
- 不会吧 - 为什么不去？
- No, no, no, no, no. - Why not?
确定不参加这么重要的活动么？
Really? Right before nationals?
你已经退出了行进乐队和机器人小组了
You already quit marching band and robotics lab.
我没有特别关注他 只是善于观察罢了
I'm not obsessed with him. I'm just very observant.
闪电 你来顶替彼得的位置吧
Flash, you're in for Peter.
噢 我不确定 我得看看我的安排表
Oof. I don't know. I gotta check my calendar first.
- 我和黑寡妇有个约会呢 - 这是不可能的
- I got a hot date with Black Widow coming up. - That is false.
我是不是说过 那个铃不是用来敲着玩的
What did I tell you about using the bell for comedic purposes?
- 嘿 哥们 - 嘿
- Hey, what's up? - Hey, man.
- 德尔马先生 你好 - 嘿 帕克
- What's up, Mr. Delmar? - Hey, Mr. Parker.
五号套餐 对吧
Number five, right?
是的 加点泡菜 能不能把它压的扁一点
Yeah, and with pickles. And can you squish it down real flat?
- 谢谢 - 没问题
- Thanks. - You got it, boss.
- 你的阿姨过的怎么样？ - 她挺好的
- How's your aunt? - She's all right.
他阿姨是个很性感的意大利美女
那你女儿呢
- 付钱吧 一共10块 - 明明是5块啊
- You know what? $10. - It's $5!
- 冲你刚刚说的那句话 你得付10块 - 嘿 我是开玩笑的
- For that comment, $10. - Hey. Come on, I'm joking. I'm joking.
给你5块
Here's $5.
你过的怎么样
How you doing, buddy?
- 在学校怎么样 - 你知道的 还是一样的无聊 我有更重要的事情要做
- How's school? - Y'know. It's boring. I got better things to do.
在学校好好学习吧 孩子 要不然你就要过上我这样的日子了
Stay in school, kids. Stay in school. Otherwise, you're gonna end up like me.
- 你过的挺好的啊 - 给你 这可是皇后区最好吃的三明治
- This is great. - Best sandwiches in Queens.
终于有目标了
Finally.
嘿 帮我拿一下这个好么 谢了
Hey, could you hold this for a second? Thanks.
嘿 这是谁的自行车
Hey, is this anybody's bike? No?
- 嘿 伙计 这是你的自行车么 - 不是
- Hey, buddy, is this your bike? - No change.
有人带笔了么 能借我支笔么
Does anyone have a pen, do you have a pen?
这是您的自行车么 如果不是的话 别偷车哟 蜘蛛侠
IS THIS YOUR BIKE? IF NOT, DON'T STEAL IT! *SPIDER-MAN
嘿 你是油管(Youtube)上的那个蜘蛛男吧
Hey, you're that Spider-guy on YouTube, right?
- 叫我蜘蛛侠！ - 好的 蜘蛛侠 来个空翻
- Call me Spider-Man! - Okay, Spider-Man. Do a flip!
- 耶！ - 不错
- Yeah! - Not bad.
- 嘿 伙计 你不该来偷车 这可不太好 - 那是我的车 白痴
- You shouldn't steal cars. It's bad. - It's my car, dumbass!
- 嘿 把警报声关掉 - 我刚刚正试图..
- Hey! Shut that off! - I was just trying to---
喂 我还要上晚班 别闹了 哥们 - 那不是你的车 那是他的车
- Yo! I work at night, come on, dude! - That's not your car. That's his car.
我怎么知道那是他的车 他干嘛撬车窗呢
How was I supposed to know it's his car? What's he doing with the window?
天天都有这些烦人的警报 把它关掉
Everyday with these damn alarms. Turn it off.
别逼我下去找你的麻烦 你个小混混
Don't make me come down there, you punk.
- 嘿 盖瑞 你过的怎么样 - 玛乔丽 你好啊
- Hey, Gary! How you doing? - Marjorie! How are you?
你妈妈还好么
How's your mother?
我没事 我没事
I'm good. I'm good.
这里是哈皮・霍根的语音邮箱
You have reached the voice mailbox of Happy Hogan.
嘿 哈皮 这是我今晚所做的报告
Hey, Happy. Here's my report for the night.
我阻止了一个自行车大盗 但我找不到失主
I stopped a grand theft bicycle. I couldn't find the owner
所以就留了张字条
so I just left a note.
我还帮助了一个迷路的老婆婆 她来自多米尼加
I helped this lost, old Dominican lady.
她人很不错 给我买了个油炸饼
She was really nice and bought me a churro.
我感觉我还能做更多的事 你懂的
I just, feel like I could be doing more, you know.
我很好奇 我们的下次任务是什么
I'm just curious when our next real mission's gonna be.
就这样 记得回我电话
So yeah, just call me back.
我是彼得・帕克
It's Peter. Parker.
我为什么要跟他说油炸饼的事
Why would I tell him about the churro?
终于可以干点大事了
Finally, something good.
这个高科技武器真是太好用了
Yo, this high tech stuff makes it too easy.
- 跟你说吧 这个买的不亏 - 快快快
- Told you it was worth it. - Go, go, go!
在复联1中洛基使用过类似的道具 用强吸力挖出眼球 此处为强化版
漂亮 我们今晚可以再抢五次了
Woah. Nice. We can hit like 5 more places tonight.
伙计们 咋回事呢 忘记取款密码了？
What's up, guys? Forgot your PIN number?
你们是复仇者啊 你们在这干什么呢
You're the Avengers! What are you guys doing here?
雷神 浩克 终于见到你们俩了
Thor. Hulk. Good to finally meet you guys.
还以为你们本人会更帅气一些呢
Thought he'd be more handsome in person.
钢铁侠！你怎么在抢银行呢？你可是百万富翁啊
Iron Man! What are you doing robbing banks? You're a billionaire.
感觉好奇怪啊
This feels so weird!
那是什么玩意？
What is that thing?
我开始觉得 你们不是复仇者了
I'm starting, to think, you're not, the Avengers!
911 有什么紧急情况？
911, what's your emergency?
蜘蛛侠和复仇者们在21街的银行里打斗
Spider-Man is fighting the Avengers in a bank on 21st street.
伙计们 别闹了 今晚还要上学呢
Alright, guys. Let's wrap this up, it's a school night.
你们这些混蛋是怎么搞到这种高科技武器的呢
So how did jerks like you get tech like this?
德尔马先生
Mr. Delmar.
嘿 德尔马先生 你在里面么 里面有人么
Hey, Mr. Delmar, you in here? Is anybody in here? Hello?
我靠
Oh, come on.
我拿着他呢
I got him...
拿着吧
Here.
好 可以 不行
Okay. Good. Yes. No, no.
放下这个 把我们俩给卖了都买不起这个
Put that down. That's worth more than you or me.
- 什么事 - 哈皮 刚刚出大事了
- Yeah? - Happy, the craziest thing just happened to me!
- 有一伙人在用高科技武器抢劫自动取款机 然后.. - 嘿 喘口气吧
- These guys were robbing an ATM with these high tech weapons, and then... - Hey, take a breath.
我可没时间管什么取款机抢劫犯 或者是你留下的什么贴心字条
Okay? I don't have time for ATM, robberies, or the thoughtful notes you leave behind.
我还有搬家的事要操心呢
I have moving day to worry about.
下周前所有东西都要搬走
Everything's gotta be out of here by next week.
- 什么？搬家的事？谁要搬家了？ - 伙计 你从来不看新闻的么
- Wait, wait. You're moving? Who's moving? - Dude, don't you watch the news?
托尼把复仇者大厦给卖了 我们要搬到纽约北部一个新的基地去
Tony sold Avengers Tower. We're relocating to a new facility upstate, where hopefully,
估计那边的手机信号会更差一些
the cell service is much worse.
- 那我怎么办？ - 什么你怎么办？
- But what about me? - What about you?
那如果史塔克先生需要我 或者什么大事发生了 我要怎么办呢？
What if Mr. Stark needs me, or something big goes down?
能不能让我和史塔克先生谈谈？
Can I please just talk to Mr. Stark?
远离那些太危险的事 我的责任是 确保你别搞出什么大乱子
Just stay away from anything too dangerous. I'm responsible for making sure you're responsible. Okay?
我是个可靠的人 靠...我的书包不见了
I am responsible! Crap... My backpack's gone.
- 你这听起来可不靠谱啊 - 我回头再打给你
- That doesn't sound responsible. - I'll call you back.
要是不打给我就更好了
Feel free not to.
- 什么情况 - 没什么 没什么
- What was that? - That's nothing! Nothing!
- 你就是油管上的那个蜘蛛侠？ - 我不是 我不是
- You're the Spider-Man. From YouTube. - I'm not. I'm not!
- 你刚刚还趴在天花板上呢 - 不 我没有
- You were on the ceiling! - No, I wasn't.
奈德 你怎么会在我的房间里呢
Ned, what are you doing in my room?
你阿姨让我进来的啊 你说过的 我们要一起把死星模型拼完的
Aunt May let me in. You said we were gonna finish the Death Star!
你不能就这么进我的房间
You can't just bust into my room.
那个火鸡肉卷菜单简直糟透了 我们出去吃吧
That turkey meat loaf recipe is a disaster. Let's go to dinner. Thai, Ned?
- 泰国餐怎么样？奈德？你想吃么？ - 不 他有点事要忙
- You want thai? - No. He's got a thing.
做事之前可以...
A thing to do, after.
好吧
Okay.
还是把衣服穿上吧
Maybe put on some clothes.
- 她不知道吧？ - 没人知道这事啊
- She doesn't know? - Nobody knows.
只有史塔克先生知道 因为这套装备是他做的 除他以外没人知道啊
Mr. Stark knows, 'cause he made my suit. But that's it.
托尼・史塔克给你做的？
Tony Stark made you that?
你加入了复仇者联盟么？
Are you an Avenger?
基本上 算是吧
Yeah. Basically.
你不能告诉别人这事 这是个秘密
You can't tell anybody about this. You gotta keep it a secret.
- 为什么是个秘密啊？ - 如果我阿姨发现
- A secret, why? - If she finds out
我每天都冒着生命危险做事 她肯定不会让我干了啊
people try and kill me every single night, she's not gonna let me do this anymore.
- 求你了 奈德 - 好吧 好吧
- C'mon Ned. Please. - Okay. Okay, okay, okay.
我跟你直说吧 我不敢保证我能严守这个秘密 这是我听说过的最酷的事啊 彼得
I'll level with you. I don't think I can keep this a secret. This is the greatest thing that's ever happened to me, Peter!
绝对不能让阿姨知道 现在还不能告诉她
May cannot know. I cannot do that to her right now.
你知道吧 她身上经历了这么多事 我...
You know? With everything that's happened with her, I...
求求你了
Please.
好的
Okay.
你要发誓绝不说出去
Just swear it. Okay?
- 我发誓 - 谢谢
- I swear. - Thank you.
真是难以置信 我居然还是被人发现了
I can't believe this is happening right now.
- 我能试试那个装备么 它的工作原理是什么 - 不行
- Can I try the suit on? How's it work? - No.
- 它是不是带磁性 你怎么发射蜘蛛丝的 - 明天去学校再说吧
- Is it magnets? How do you shoot the strings? - I'm gonna tell you about this at school tomorrow. Okay?
好吧 等等..
Great. Wait, then...
你是如何同时兼顾这事和在史塔克工业的实习的？
How do you do this, and the Stark internship?
这就是我在史塔克工业的实习内容
This is the Stark internship.
快走吧
Just get out.
怎么了 我还以为你喜欢泰餐呢
What's the matter? I thought you loved larb.
是太有泰国特色了么？还是泰国特色不足？
It's too larby? Not larby enough.
我还得跟你说多少句话 你才肯回答我？
How many times do I have to say 'larb' before, you talk to me?
你知道的 我很关心你
You know I 'larb' you.
我很焦虑 实习搞得我太累了 太多活要干了
I'm just stressed. The internship, and I'm tired. A lotta work.
在史塔克工业的实习么？我跟你说
The Stark internship? I have to tell you...
我个人可不看好托尼・史塔克
Not a fan of that Tony Stark.
一直让我心烦意乱
Distracted all the time...
在脑中挥之不去
It's got you in your head.
本地新闻 皇后区深受欢迎的德尔马三明治店今晚早些时候发生爆炸
...in local news, the beloved Queens institution, Delmar Sandwiches was destroyed in an
店面受损严重 此前 皇后区的
explosion earlier tonight, after an ATM robbery was
罪犯阻止者 蜘蛛侠
thwarted by Queens own colorful, local
试图阻止一伙劫匪抢劫自动取款机
crime-stopper, the Spider-Man. As the Spider-Man
打斗过程中 突然出现了一道强力的冲击波
attempted to foil their heist, a powerful blast was set off,
直接穿过马路 引发爆炸
slicing through the bodega across the street.
万幸的是 无人受伤
Miraculously, no one was harmed.
要是看到了这样的事 你要掉头就跑
You spot something like that happening, you turn and you run the other way.
是的 当然
Yeah. Of course.
- 那就发生在离我们六条街的地方！ - 我要换一个新背包
- Six blocks away from us! - I need a new backpack.
- 你说什么？ - 我要一个新背包
- What? - I need a new backpack.
你都换了五个了
That's a five.
- 这是糯米补丁 - 我们没点这个菜
- Sticky rice pudding. - Oh, we didn't order that.
- 这是本店赠送的 - 谢谢
- It's on the house. - Oh. Thanks.
他真是个好人
That's nice of him.
我觉得 他也很关心你
I think, he 'larbs' you.
你被蜘蛛咬了一口？它能咬我一口么
You got bit by a spider? Can it bite me?
应该不会太疼吧
It probably wouldn't hurt, right?
算了 无论疼不疼 我都愿意让它咬我 也许吧 那得有多疼啊
Y'know what, whatever. Even if it did hurt, I'll let it bite me. Maybe. How much did it hurt?
那个蜘蛛已经死了 奈德
The spider's dead, Ned.
你当时在场？
You were here?
是啊
Yeah.
你当时可能会丢命的
You could've died.
- 你会产卵么？ - 你问什么？当然不会啊
- Do you lay eggs? - What? No.
- 你会喷射毒液么？ - 不会啊
- Can you spit venom? - No.
- 你能召集蜘蛛大军么？ - 不能 奈德
- Can you summon an army of spiders? - No, Ned.
索科维亚协议生效了
The Sokovia Accords were put into place, and...
索科维亚协议：由联合国在内战中制定 用来约束复联成员
你的网能射多远
How far can you shoot your webs?
不知道 闭嘴吧 别问了
Don't know. Shut up.
如果我是你 我就站在一栋高楼楼顶
If I was you, I would stand on the edge of a building and just
用力射出去 看看有多远
shoot it as far as I can...
闭嘴 奈德
Shut up, Ned.
嗨 我是美国队长 无论你是在课堂里 还是在战场上
Hi. I'm Captain America. Whether you're in the classroom, or on the battlefield...
- 你也认识他么 - 是啊 我见过他
- Do you know him, too? - Yeah. We've met.
我偷过他的盾牌
I stole his shield.
今天 我的好朋友 你们的体育老师
Today, my good friend, your gym teacher,
将会带你们进行"美国队长体能挑战"
will be conducting the "Captain America Fitness Challenge."
谢谢 美国队长 虽然我敢肯定这家伙已经是罪犯了
Thank you, Captain. I'm pretty sure this guy's a war criminal now
不管怎么说 我还是得给你们看这视频 这是国家要求的 准备训练吧
but whatever. I have to show these videos, it's required by the state. Let's do it.
复仇者们也需要交税么？
Do Avengers have to pay taxes?
浩克问起来是啥味道？我敢肯定他闻起来很香
复仇者们也需要交税么？
What does Hulk smell like? I bet he smells nice.
Do Avengers have to pay taxes?
浩克问起来是啥味道？我敢肯定他闻起来很香
What does Hulk smell like? I bet he smells nice.
- 奈德 闭嘴吧 - 美国队长长得帅么
- Ned, shut up. - Is Captain America cool?
- 还是他只是个刻薄的老头？ - 奈德 别问了 行么？
- Or is he like a mean, old grandpa? - Ned, just shh. Okay?
嘿
Hey...
- 我能不能当你的幕后指挥？ - 你说什么
- Can I be your guy in the chair? - What?
你知道的 就是那种 戴个耳机 给手下的人下命令的
You know how there's a guy, with a headset, telling the other guy where to go? Like...
比如 你被困在了一栋公寓楼里 我可以告诉你怎么逃出去 我四周有很多屏幕
Like if you're stuck in an apartment building, I could tell you where to go, 'cause there'd be screens around me...
我可以绕着显示屏走动 就是这种幕后指挥
And I could swivel around them 'cause I'd be your guy in the chair.
- 奈德 我不需要幕后指挥 - 做的不错 帕克
- Ned, I don't need a guy in the chair. - Looking good, Barker.
要我选的话 我要上了索尔
Now see, for me, it would be, F Thor...
嫁给钢铁侠 杀了浩克
Marry Iron Man and kill Hulk.
- 那蜘蛛侠呢 - 蜘蛛侠只是个小角色啦
- Well what about the Spider-Man? - It's just Spider-Man.
你们看到油管上的那个监控录像么？ 他一个人解决了4个呢
And did you guys see that security cam on YouTube? He fought off 4 guys!
- 我的天 她看上蜘蛛侠了 - 不是吧
- Oh, my gosh. She's crushing on Spider-Man. - No way.
- 有点吧 - 真恶心
- Kind of! - Ugh. Gross.
- 估计他已经30岁了 - 你连他长什么样都不知道
- He's probably like, 30. - You don't even know what he looks like.
如果他以前重度烧伤 全身疤痕呢
What if he's like, seriously burned?
我无所谓 我爱的是他的内在
I wouldn't care. I would still love him for the person he is inside.
彼得认识蜘蛛侠
Peter knows Spider-Man.
- 我不认识 我... - 他们是朋友
- No, I don't. No. I mean... - They're friends.
是啊 美国队长还是体育老师的朋友呢
Yeah, like Coach Wilson and Captain America are friends.
我见过他 见过几次 但是..
I've met him. Yeah. A couple of times. But it's, umm...
那是我在史塔克工业实习的时候
Through the Stark internship.
嗯 我觉得我们不应该谈这个的
Yeah. I'm not really supposed to talk about it.
那真是太酷了 你可以邀请他参加丽兹的派对呢
Well that's awesome! Hey, you know what? Maybe you should invite him to Liz' party, right?
嗯 我今晚要开个派对 非常欢迎你来
Yeah, I'm having people over tonight. You're more than welcome to come.
- 你要开派对？ - 是啊 肯定会玩的很嗨
- You're having a party? - Yeah. It's gonna be dope.
你可得把你的蜘蛛侠朋友请来了
You should totally invite your personal friend Spider-Man.
没关系 我知道彼得
It's okay. I know Peter's way
很忙的 没时间参加派对 所以...
too busy for parties anyway, so...
不不 他会来的 对吧 帕克？
Aw, c'mon. He'll be there. Right, Parker?
- 你在搞什么鬼 - 我在帮你啊
- What are you doing? - Helping you out.
你没听到她说的么 丽兹看上你了
Did you not hear her? Liz has a crush on you.
兄弟 你是个复仇者啊 要说我们中的谁最有希望
Dude, you're an Avenger. If any one of us has a chance with
和高年级的女生约会 那肯定就是你了
a senior girl, it's you.
丽兹的家在郊区 我记得的
House party in the suburbs! I remember these.
- 我有点嫉妒了 - 这肯定会是难忘的一夜
- I'm kinda jealous! - It'll be a night to remember.
奈德..
Aww... Ned...
一般来说 都是帽子挑人 而你这个 绝对是你挑帽子
Some hats wear men. You wear that hat.
是啊 这顶帽子让我信心十足
Yeah. It gives me confidence.
这不太妙 我们还是回家吧
This is a mistake. Hey, let's just go home.
彼得 我明白 对你来说 参加集体活动是件困难的事
Oh, Peter. I know. I know it's really hard, trying to fit in.
你的身体经历了一系列变化 已经成熟了
With all the changes your body is going through. It's flowering now.
他最近压力很大
He's so stressed out lately.
参加派对有助于缓解压力 所以你应该参加派对
What helps with stress, is going to a party. And you should have a party.
行 走吧 走吧
Yeah. I'm gonna go. I'm gonna go.
- 彼得 好好玩 - 我会的
- Peter! Have fun. Okay? - I will.
再见 梅！
Bye, May!
兄弟 装备你带了没
Dude, you have the suit, right?
这简直太刺激了
This is gonna change our lives!
让蜘蛛侠晃进来 就说你们俩关系很铁
We're gonna have Spider-Man swing in, say you guys are tight, and then I get...
然后我来跟他对上几拳
a fist bump for one of those half bro bumps.
真不敢相信 你们俩居然来参加派对了
I can't believe you guys are at this lame party.
你不是也来了么
You're here, too.
是么
Am I?
我的天 你们好啊 奈德 帽子不错
Oh, my gosh. Hey, guys! Cool hat, Ned.
- 你好 丽兹 - 你好 丽兹
- Hi, Liz! - Hi, Liz.
很高兴看到你们来这
I'm so happy you guys came.
这儿有披萨 饮料 随便拿吧
There's pizza, and drinks. Help yourself.
- 这派对真不错 - 谢谢夸奖
- What a great party. - Thanks.
- 要是他们打碎了什么东西 我爸妈要打死我的 所以我去.. - 好的
- My parents will kill me if anything's broken. I gotta... - Yeah.
- 玩的开心 - 拜
- Have fun. - Bye.
哥们 你愣着干嘛呢
Dude! What are you doing?
她就在这呢 蜘蛛侠变身啊
She's here. Spider-Man up!
不不不 这样不行
No, no, no. I cannot do this.
蜘蛛侠可不是什么派对上玩的把戏 我还是
Spider-Man's not a party trick. Okay? Look, I'm just gonna...
做我自己就好
Be myself.
- 彼得 他们想看的不是你啊 - 兄弟
- Peter, no one wants that. - Dude.
你好啊
Penis Parker!
你那个蜘蛛侠哥们在哪呢
What's up? So where's your pal Spider-Man?
让我猜猜 是不是和你幻想中的女朋友
Let me guess. He's stranded with your imaginary girlfriend?
你旁边的可不是蜘蛛侠 只是穿着红衣服的奈德而已啊
That's not Spider-Man. That's just Ned in a red shirt.
嘿 大家好 我是蜘蛛侠
Hey, what's up? I'm Spider-Man.
我就是过来和我的哥们彼得打个招呼
Just thought I'd swing by and say hello to my boy Peter.
奈德 你好啊 彼得在哪呢 他应该就在附近..
Oh, what's up, Ned? Hey, where's Peter anyway? He must be over...
妈的 这简直太蠢了 我在干什么呢
God, this is stupid. What am I doing?
什么情况
What the hell?
这玩意是用从索科维亚回收来的次奥创战士手臂 加工制成的
Now this is crafted from a reclaimed sub-Ultron arm straight from Sokovia.
给你 来试试
Here. You try.
兄弟 我只想买点低调的武器 干嘛给我展示这种的
Man, I wanted something low-key, like... Why you tryin' to outsell me, man?
好好好 肯定有你看得上眼的东西 别急 我这里不错的玩意可多了
Ok, ok, ok. I got what you need, alright? I got tons of great stuff here.
等一下
One sec.
- 我这有黑洞手雷 奇塔瑞轨道炮 - 真是丢人
- Okay. I got, black hole grenades, Chitauri rail guns... - ... Letting off shots in public.
我知道什么适合你 时代不同了
No, I hear you. Look, times are changing, and
我们是唯一一家出售这些高科技武器的
we're the only ones selling these high tech weapons.
那些取款机抢劫犯肯定是从这搞到的武器
This must be where the ATM robbers got their stuff.
我只想要点小打小闹的武器 可不想把人一枪打到另外一个时空
I just need something to stakeout somebody. I'm not trying to shoot them back in time.
- 我这还有反重力攀登器 - 你们这还有攀登器？
- I got anti-grav climbers... - You have climbers?
什么情况？
Okay, what the hell was that?
- 你给我们下套？ - 嘿 兄弟 别急
- Did you set us up? - Hey, hey, man!
嘿 你们想开枪的话 来打我啊！
Hey, hey. C'mon! You're gonna shoot at somebody, shoot at me!
您好啊
All right.
震荡拳套：内战中"交叉骨"使用过的武器 另一只随"交叉骨"自爆而毁
那是什么啊
What was that?
- 打个电话给他吧 - 不不不
- We gotta call him. - Nah, nah, nah, nah!
- 你又用那玩意了？ - 闭嘴
- Did you just do it again? - Shut up!
我要打给他了
I'm calling him.
我是图姆斯
Toomes' phone.
老大
Boss...
嗷 我的屁股
Oww. My butt.
丫的 看样子我要抄个近路了
Great. Guess I'm gonna have to take a shortcut.
嘿 各位 祝你们玩的开心
Hey, guys. Good game. Have fun.
伙计 抱歉 我没时间陪你玩 去把它捡回来
Hey! Buddy! Sorry, no time to play. Here. Go fetch!
真刺激啊！
Now this is more like it!
闻起来很不错哦！
Smells really good!
这一段庭院跑酷追车镜头致敬经典电影《春天不是读书天》
电影不错！
Great movie!
嘿 小女孩们
Oh, hey guys.
- 嘿 我是彼得 给我留言吧 - 彼得 你在哪呢
- Hey, it's Peter. Leave a message. - Peter, where are you?
计划不是这样的 这可不太好啊
The hat's not working. This is not cool.
差点抓到你了！
Almost got ya!
你还以为能逃出我的手掌心呢
Thought you'd get away from me, didn't you?
抓到你了！
I gotcha! Right where I want you!
我来啦！
Surprise!
搞什么鬼
What the hell?
嘿
Oh. Hey.
然后 他就像个怪物一样俯冲下来
And then, he's, he just, like swooped down, like a monster. And he picked me up...
把我抓住 拖到到了一千英尺的高空 再扔下来
and took me over like 1000 feet and just dropped me.
你是怎么找到我的 在我的装备上放了追踪器？
How did you find me? Did you put a tracker on my suit or something?
我给你装的东西可多了
I put everything in your suit.
其中就包括这个加热器
Including this heater.
- 好多了 谢谢 - 你在想什么呢
- That's better. Thanks. - What were you thinking?
那个戴着翅膀的家伙肯定就是这些武器的源头 我得拿下他
The guy with the wings is obviously the source of the weapons. I gotta take him down.
拿下他？
Take him down now, huh?
- 消停点吧 小英雄 会有人来搞定他们的 - 复仇者么
- Steady, Crockett. There are people who handle this sort of thing. - The Avengers?
Crockett：大卫・克洛科特 美国19世纪著名的民族英雄[四七注]
不不不 他们拿那么高的工资 可不是干这个的
No, no, no. This is a little below their paygrade.
不管怎么说 史塔克先生 您不用跑这么大老远的 我能搞定的 没事的
Anyway, Mr. Stark. You didn't have to come all the way out here. I had that. I was fine.
其实 我本人并没有..在这里
Oh, I'm not... here.
谢天谢地 这地方还有wifi信号 要不然你就玩完了
Thank God, this place has Wi-Fi, or you would be toast right now.
谢谢你 加内什
Thank Ganesh while you're at it.
- 听我说 你就别管那个翅膀男了 - 为什么
- Look, forget the flying Vulture guy. Please! - Why?
因为我叫你忘了他
Why? Because I said so!
不好意思 我正在跟一个小孩子通电话
Sorry. I'm talking to a teenager.
脚踏实地 做点小事情 帮助一下周围的普通人
Stay close to the ground. Build up your game, helping the little people.
比如那个给你买油炸饼的女士
Like that lady that bought you the churro.
为什么就不能好好当一个 友善的 乐于帮助邻居的蜘蛛侠呢？
Can't you just be like a friendly, neighborhood Spider-Man?
但是我已经准备好大展身手了
But I'm ready for more than that now.
不 你并没有
No, you're not.
当我搞定美国队长的时候 你可不是这么说的
That is not what you thought when I took on Captain America.
相信我 孩子 要他想搞定你 他就能搞定你
Trust me, kid. If Cap wanted to lay you out, he would have.
听我说 如果你再看到这些武器 联系哈皮
Listen to me. If you come across these weapons again, call Happy.
你在开车吗？
Are you driving?
我跟你说 考虑一下读大学的事 越早越好
You know, it's never too early to start thinking about college.
我在麻省理工大学认识些人 通话结束
I got some pull at MIT. End call.
- 不 我不需要读大学 史塔克先生... - 史塔克先生已经离线
- No, I don't need to go to college, Mr. Stark... - Mr. Stark is no longer connected.
我了个去
That's awesome.
脚踏实地 他这是在说什么呢？
Stay close to the ground. What is he talking about?
- 老兄 怎么了 我正在回去的路上 - 其实我打电话给你 就是想说 你也许不该回来了 听听这个...
- Hey, man, what's up? I'm on my way back. - Actually, I was calling to say maybe you shouldn't come. Listen to this.
当我说"屁颠儿"  你说"帕克"
... When I say "Penis", you say "Parker"!
抱歉 帕克 我觉得我们俩还是潘 明天见吧
Sorry, Peter. I guess we're still losers. I'll see you tomorrow.
明天学校见
I'll see you tomorrow in school.
白痴
Idiots.
白痴 一群白痴！
Idiots. Idiots!
老大
Boss?
你老婆一直在给你发短信 是关于什么刹车灯的事儿
Your wife keeps texting you. Something about a brake light?
我不是不让你看我手机吗？
What'd I tell you about looking at my phone?
抱歉 你忘带手机了 你知道的 我天生好奇心强
Oh, sorry. You left it out. You know I'm a curious person by nature.
我已经完成了那个高海拔真空密封的设计
I've finished designing that high altitude vacuum seal...
也许哪天你想干一票大的
In case you wanna, you know, go for the big one?
你还在做那个东西？我跟你说过 别管那个了
You're still on that? I told you, no. The answer's no. Forget it!
太牛了
That was badass.
我告诉过你多少遍了 不要在外面开火
How many times have I told you... Not to fire them out in the open?
- 你说过要把东西卖出去啊 - 低调点 低调点！
- You said move the merchandise! - Under the radar. Under the radar!
这是我们的生存之道
That's how we survive.
如果你引来灾害控制部门或者复仇者到这儿 我们就完了
If you bring Damage Control, or the Avengers down here, we're through.
而你就在外面穿着那个愚蠢的装扮 灯光全开
And you're out there, wearing that goofy thing, lighting up cars...
还称呼自己为"惊悚" 我外表惊悚 我让人们恐惧
Calling yourself "The Shocker." I'm the Shocker. I shock people.
- 这算什么 职业摔跤手么？ - 随你怎么说吧 老顽固
- What is this, pro wrestling? - Yeah, whatever, old man. C'mon.
听着 听着
Look, look.
我知道你根本不在乎这些 但我在乎
I know, you don't give a crap about anything. But I do.
我干这行 是因为我要养家糊口
I built this whole place because I got people I have to look after.
是 是 是 是
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
你知道么？我受不了你这么折腾了
You know what? I can't afford your bullshit.
- 你走吧 - 什么？
- Get outta here. - What?!
- 你完了 你被开除了 - 好 没问题
- You're done, you're off the crew. - Yeah. Alright.
不过我很好奇 你能不能受得了我在外面折腾
I wonder if you can afford me out there...
- 这里的事我可一清二楚 - 你再说一遍？
- With everything I know. - Excuse me?
我是想说...
I'm just saying...
也许你老婆会想知道你的钱是从哪儿来的
Maybe your wife would like to know where you really get your money from.
- 你知道吗？ - 什么？
- You know what? - What?
你说对了
You're right.
- 这东西好使吗？ - 我不知道
- That work? - I don't know.
我确实受不了
I can't afford that.
天啊
Damn!
- 我还以为这个是反重力枪 - 什么？
- I thought this was the anti-gravity gun. - What?!
不 那个才是
No. That's that one.
给
Here.
现在你是"惊悚" 去把他弄丢的武器找回来
Now you're the Shocker. Go out there and find that weapon he lost.
好的
Right.
- 嘿 多谢你来帮我 - 嗯 出了点状况
- Hey, thanks for bailing on me. - Yeah, well, something came up.
- 那是什么？ - 我不知道
- What is that? - I don't know.
- 有人想用这个把我蒸发了 - 真的？
- Some guy tried to vaporize me with it. - Seriously?
- 对 - 真酷
- Yeah. - Awesome!
我是说 不酷
I mean, not awesome.
一点都不酷 那些家伙太可怕了
Totally uncool, that guy. So scary.
看 我想这应该是个电源
Well look. I think it's a power source.
嗯 但它和这些微型处理器都连在一起
Yeah, but it's connected to all those microprocessors.
这是一个感应充电板 我就是用这个来给牙刷充电的
It's an inductive charging plate. That's what I use to charge my toothbrush.
不管是谁做了这些武器 肯定都是利用了外星科技
Whoever's making these weapons is obviously combining the alien tech with ours.
这简直是人类有史以来最酷的一句话
That is literally the coolest sentence anyone has ever said.
感谢你让我加入这个不可思议的冒险
I just wanna thank you for letting me be a part of your journey, into this amazing...
小心你的手指不要被刀切到
Keep your fingers clear of the blades.
我得弄清楚这是什么并且是谁做的
I gotta figure out what this thing is and who makes it.
咱们下课后去实验室做些试验
We'll go to the lab after class and run some tests.
首先 我建议我们先测一下发光物的质量
First, I say we put the glowy thing in the mass ().
我觉得还是先给"发光物"起个名字比较好
First, we gotta come up with a better name than "glowy thingy".
你说得对
You're right.
糟了 过来 过来 快过来
Crap! Come on, come on, come on.
高中都把我逼疯了
High schools creep me out.
它这里的味道 你懂我意思吧
It's got this funny smell, you know what I mean?
- 其中一个就是之前试图杀我的人 - 什么？
- That's one of the guys that tried to kill me. - What?
- 我们得赶紧离开这儿 - 不不不 我们得跟着他们
- We gotta get out of here. - No, no, no. We got to follow them.
也许他们能带我找到把我扔进湖里的人
Maybe they can lead me to the guy that dropped me in a lake.
- 有人把你扔进了湖里？ - 对啊 那感觉太糟了
- Someone dropped you in a lake? - Yeah. It was not good.
- 彼得 - 待在这儿 奈德
- Peter. - No. Stay there, Ned.
彼得！
Peter!
- 你在干嘛呢 - 没干嘛
- What are you doing? - Nothing.
嗯 你呢
Yeah. You good?
在下棋
Chess?
你能想象如果老大知道我们在这里会说什么吗？
Can you imagine what the boss would say if he knew where we were?
我说了这里感应到了一股能量脉冲
I'm saying there was an energy pulse right here.
这里连个武器的影都没有 就算它之前在这里 现在也不在了
There's no sign of the weapon. I mean, even if it was here, now it's gone.
我们也走吧
So are we...
这太牛了
This is so awesome.
我知道
I know, right.
现在在布鲁克林
In Brooklyn.
斯塔腾岛
Staten Island.
正在离开新泽西
Leaving Jersey.
他们不动了
They stopped.
- 马里兰？ - 那儿有什么？
- Maryland? - What's there?
我不知道 他们的邪恶老巢？
I don't know, evil lair?
- 邪恶老巢？ - 哥们 一个翅膀男率领的有外星武器的一群人
- Evil lair? - Dude, a gang with alien guns run by a guy with wings,
- 没错 他们肯定有老巢 - 够劲爆
- yeah, they have a lair. - Badass.
但是 那地方离这儿至少有300英里远 你打算怎么过去呢？
But, how are you gonna get there if that's like, 300 miles away?
那儿离华盛顿很近
It's not too far from DC.
- 是彼得！ - 朋友们！
- Hey, it's Peter! - Guys!
- 我在想我能不能重新回到队伍里 - 不 没门儿
- Yeah, I was hoping maybe I could rejoin the team. - No. No way.
你不能退出队伍了 还指望大家欢迎你回来
You can't just quit on us, stroll up, and be welcomed back by everyone.
欢迎回来 彼得！闪电 你继续当替补
Hey, welcome back, Peter! Flash, you're back to first alternate.
- 什么？ - 你的位置现在是他的了
- What? - He's taking your place!
抱歉 咱们是不是可以出发了？
Excuse me, can we go already?
因为我希望晚餐前能参加一个在大使馆门前举行的抗议活动 所以...
'Cause I was hoping to get in some light protesting in front of one of the embassies before dinner, so...
抗议是爱国的表现 我们出发吧
Protesting is patriotic. Let's get on the bus.
注意了 各位 下一个主题是土星的卫星
Focus up, everyone. Our next topic is the moons of Saturn.
- 热力学第二定律 - 法兰克・辛纳屈
- The second law of Thermodynamics. - Frank Sinatra.
- 萨普特堡垒 - 闪电说错了
- Fort Sumpter. - Flash is wrong.
- 好了各位 集中注意 下一题 - 丽兹 别让他们太累了
- Okay guys, let's focus. Next one. - Liz, don't overwork 'em.
- 锶 钡 振金 - 很好 彼得 很高兴你能回来
- Strontium, Barium, Vibranium. - Very good, Peter. Glad to have you back.
振金：产自黑豹的祖国瓦坎达 美队的盾牌和奥创的身体皆为振金所做
我也是
Glad to be back.
...单位的初速电流状态是...
What is the current state of unit...
- 我能接个电话吗 很快就回来 - 好 没事
- Can I take this real quick? I'll only be a second. - Yeah, fine.
- 喂？ - 我这边屏幕出现了点波动 你离开纽约了？
- Hello? - I got a blip on my screen here. You left New York?
跟踪器 啊 对...
Tracker. Uh, yeah...
只是学校组织的外出活动而已 没什么的 哈皮...
No, it's just a school trip, it's nothing. Look, Happy...
我必须得说 你没经过我允许就监视我 这侵犯了我的个人隐私
I gotta say, you tracking me without my permission is a complete violation of my privacy.
- 这不一样 - 什么不一样？
- That's different. - What's different?
没什么 这就是一个学术十项全能比赛
Nothing. Look, it's just the academic decathlon.
- 不是什么大事 - 是不是大事 我说了算
- It's no big deal. - Hey. I'll decide if it's no big deal.
不过听起来确实不是什么大事 但是记住了 我盯着你呢
Sounds like it's no big deal. But remember, I'm watching you.
- 大家跟紧点不要走散了 - 好
- Everyone stick together. - Yeah.
不是逗我吧？这地方可真大！
Are you kidding me? This place is huge!
- 我见过更大的 - 那里有只鸟
- I've seen bigger. - There's a bird in here.
- 你带了手提电脑吧 - 怎么了？
- Hey, you brought your laptop, right? - Why?
彼得 我们为什么要把你装备里的跟踪器取出来？
Peter, why are we removing the tracker from your suit?
因为我想在那些人再次移动前 顺藤摸瓜找到他们的老大
Because I gotta follow these guys to their boss before they move again...
而且我不想让史塔克先生知道这件事
And I don't really want Mr. Stark to know about it.
- 所以你是在对钢铁侠撒谎？ - 不 我没在撒谎
- So you're lying to Iron Man now? - No, I'm not lying.
他就是不知道我现在能做什么
He just doesn't really get what I can do yet.
搞定
Gotcha.
好了 哈皮 祝你追踪台灯愉快
Alright, Happy. Enjoy tracking this lamp.
这里还有许多其他的子系统
There's a ton of other subsystems in here.
但是它们全部被这个"辅助轮协议"关闭了
But they're all disabled by the... "Training Wheels Protocol".
什么？辅助轮协议？
What? The Training Wheels Protocol?
- 关掉它 - 我不认为这是个好主意 你瞧...
- Turn it off. - I don't think that's a good idea, I mean...
他们关掉这个是有原因的
They're probably blocked for a reason.
来吧老兄 我可不需要什么辅助车轮
Come on, man. I don't need training wheels.
我受够了 他一直把我当小孩子一样看待
I'm sick of him treating me like a kid all the time.
- 一点都不酷 - 但你确实还是个孩子
- It's not cool. - But you are a kid.
是啊 一个可以徒手拦住公交车的孩子
Yeah. A kid who can stop a bus with his bare hands.
彼得 我就是觉得这个主意不好 万一这样是违法的呢
Peter, I just don't think this is a great idea. I mean, what if this is illegal?
听着 这是一个可以让我证明自己的机会
Look, please. This is my chance to prove myself.
- 我能搞定的 奈德 - 我真不觉得这是个好主意
- I can handle it. Ned, come on. - I really don't think this is a good idea.
- 你可是我的幕后指挥啊 - 你啊你！
- But, guy in the chair. - Don't do that!
老兄
Come on.
那个发光物是重要的证据 一定要保管好 好吗？
Hey. The glowy thing is evidence. Keep it safe, all right?
没问题
Okay.
- 我走了 - 小心点
- I'm moving. - Be careful.
- 嗨 丽兹 - 你来的正好 我们正要去游泳呢
- Hey, Liz. - Perfect timing. We're gonna go swimming.
快来 快来
Come on! Come on.
嗨 彼得
Hey, Peter.
我正要去商业中心复习来着
I was gonna go study, in the, business center.
彼得 你不需要复习 你是我见过最聪明的人
Peter, you don't need to study. You're like the smartest guy I've ever met.
另外...
And besides...
在比赛前一天 搞一个叛逆的集体活动对士气有帮助
A rebellious group activity the day before competition is good for morale.
啊 我也是在TED演讲上看的 所以...
Um, I read that in a TED talk, so...
我在TED演讲上听到的
I heard it in a TED talk.
还读过一本指导手册
And I read a coaching book.
你真的很看重这次比赛吗？
Are you really, this is really important to you?
是的 这事关大家的前程
Yeah. It's our future.
我不想搞砸了
I'm not gonna screw it up.
而且我们刚刚还去搜刮了一些冰箱里的食物 这些糖果只要11块钱
And besides, we raided the minibar and these candy bars were like $11.
所以赶紧收拾一下过来吧
So get your trunks on and come on.
- 快来啊 快来啊 - 我来啦
- Come on. Come on. - I'm coming!
- 晚上好 彼得 - 谁在说话？
- Good evening, Peter. - Hello?
恭喜你通过了严格的辅助轮协议
Congratulations on completing your rigorous Training Wheels Protocol.
并且获得装备的全部功能
And gaining access to your suit's full capabilities.
- 啊 谢谢 - 那么你今晚打算带我去哪？
- Ah, thank you. - So where would you like to take me tonight?
我把跟踪器放到一个坏人身上了
I put a tracker on someone. He's a bad guy.
跟踪器已定位
Tracker located.
正在规划路线拦截目标
Plotting course to intercept target.
好的 只要能让我及时赶回十项全能比赛就可以
Okay well, as long as I make it back in time for decathlon, it's fine.
距离目的地还有100米
100 meters from destination and closing.
现在跳下去
Jump now.
检测到三个目标
Detecting three individuals.
为什么他们的秘密基地是在加油站？也太磕碜了
Why is their secret lair in a gas station? That's so lame.
- 战衣姐姐 他们在干嘛？ - 你想听到他们的谈话吗？
- Hey, suit lady, what are they doing? - Do you wanna hear what they're saying?
我还能听到他们在说什么？当然想
I can hear what they're saying? Uhh, yeah.
激活增强性侦查模式
Activating Enhanced Reconnaissance mode.
我在拉各斯的清理物中找到了一个金属手套 其余的都是我的
I got the gauntlet from the Lagos cleanup. The rest is all mine.
哇哦 太酷炫了
Whoa. That's so cool.
不敢相信他们还在清理三曲枝大厦的垃圾
Can't believe they're still cleaning up that Triskelion mess.
三曲枝大厦：神盾局前总部大楼 在美队2中被一艘空天母舰撞毁
这样最好 他们继续乱作一团 咱们闷声发大财
I love it. They keep making messes, we keep getting rich.
- 目标进站了 - 哇 他们打算抢劫
- Target inbound. - Whoa, they're in the middle of a heist.
我可以当场抓住他们 棒极了
I can catch them all red-handed. This is awesome!
好了 我得再靠近一点去看看发生了什么
Okay, I'm gonna get a little closer so I can see what's happening.
你想开启增强性战斗模式吗？
Would you like me to engage Enhanced Combat mode?
"增强性战斗模式"？好啊
"Enhanced Combat mode"? Yeah.
- 启动一击必杀功能 - 不不不 我不打算杀任何人
- Activating Instant Kill. - No, no, no, no. I don't wanna kill anybody.
关闭一击必杀功能
Deactivating Instant Kill.
你听到了吗？
Did you hear that?
刚才发生了什么？那是什么？
What the hell just happened? What was that?
你从广告牌上跳下来 脸部着地
You jumped off the sign and landed on your face.
战衣姐姐 我的蛛网发射器是怎么回事？
Suit lady, what's wrong with my web shooters?
快速射击是增强性战斗模式的默认功能
Rapid-fire is the default for Enhanced Combat mode.
- 我为什么会需要快速射击？ - 你想要查看更多的选项吗？
- Why would I need Rapid-fire? - Would you like to see more options?
你总共有576种射击组合可供选择
You have 576 possible web shooter combinations.
- 史塔克先生用力过猛了 - 你们两个在这儿等着
- Mr. Stark really overdid it. - You two wait right here.
等下 你需要打开减震器不然你的手臂会被震碎
Wait, you're gonna wanna turn on the dampers or that thing will shatter your arm.
- 减震器在哪？ - 就选这个了！
- Where's the dampers? - That one!
明智的选择 你想把它设定为新的默认设置吗？
Great choice! Would you like me to set this as your new default?
- 不不不 - 把它按下去...
- No, no, no! - Push that in...
- 这里吗？ - 不不不 对 按下去
- Right here? - No, no. Yeah, push it.
- 那是什么？ - 电击蛛网
- What was that? - Taser webs.
电击蛛网？我不需要电击蛛网
Taser webs? I don't want taser webs.
你看起来对你的蛛网射击设置很不熟悉
You seem to be very unfamiliar with your web shooter settings.
- 你想要复习一下设置教程吗？ - 不 你给我选好了
- Would you like to run a refresher course? - No, just, you choose.
- 没问题 - 6-9-9 你能按时到达吗？
- Sure thing. - 6-Alpha-Niner, are you running on time?
收到 指挥中心 6-9-9 尚未超时
Copy, Central. 6-Alpha-Niner, on schedule.
- 发现目标 - 开始行动
- I have a visual. - Green light. Green light.
就是他
That's him.
很好 我看到车队了
Okay. I got eyes on the convoy.
正在靠近目标车辆
Pulling in behind the caboose.
放下固定锚
Deploy anchors.
准备下落
Dropping down.
没有发现危险信号 一切安全
No outgoing distress signals. You're all clear.
看起来他们这儿有不少好东西
Looks like they got some good stuff here.
真酷 看起来像某种物质相态转换装置
Cool. It's like some kind of matter phase shifter.
好了 准备上去
All right. Coming up.
嘿 大鸟 这可不是你的东西
Hey, big bird! This doesn't belong to you!
我的天
Oh, God.
- 战衣姐姐 那又是什么？ - 你让我来选择的
- Suit lady, what was that? - You told me to choose.
什么？不 把一切恢复正常就好
What, no. Just set everything back to normal!
激活全部系统
Activating all systems.
- 噢 我的头 - 你似乎有轻微的脑震荡
- Oh. My head. - You appear to have a mild concussion.
- 我这是在什么地方？ - 我不确定
- So, where am I right now? - I'm not sure.
集装箱的墙壁屏蔽了我的传感器
The container walls are hindering my sensors.
等一下
Wait a minute.
他们一定是劫持了卡车 还带我去了他们的邪恶老巢
They must've hijacked the truck and taken me to their evil lair.
好吧战衣姐姐 看来我们这次得杀出重围了
Okay. So maybe we're gonna have to fight our way out of this one.
三 二 一！
Three, two, one!
这是什么地方？战衣姐姐 我在哪儿？
What is this place? Suit lady, where am I?
你正在整个东海岸最安全的地方
You're in the most secure facility on the eastern seaboard.
灾害控制部门的深度存储库
The Damage Control deep storage vault.
不是吧 别这样
No! Seriously?
这扇门很可能会一直关到明天早上
The door will most likely remain closed until morning.
明天早上？
Morning?
战衣姐姐 我开始觉得叫你"战衣姐姐"是不是不太好
Hey, suit lady. I kinda feel bad calling you "Suit Lady", you know?
我应该给你起个名字
I think I should probably give you a name.
比如丽兹 不不不 天啊 这太变态了
Like Liz. No, no, no. God, that's weird.
- 凯伦怎么样？ - 如果你喜欢的话当然可以叫我凯伦
- What about KAREN? - You can call me KAREN if you'd like.
凯伦 这个装备还能干什么？
Hey, KAREN. What else can this suit do?
哇 也许我真该复习一下设置教程
What? Maybe we should run that refresher course.
- 弹跳网 - 弹跳网
- Ricochet web. - Ricochet web.
真酷 分离网
- Cool. - Stutter web.
- 蛛网手雷 - 蛛网手雷！
- Web grenade. - Web grenade!
我该告诉丽兹我就是蜘蛛侠吗？
Should I tell Liz that I'm Spider-Man?
- 谁是丽兹？ - 谁是丽兹？
- Who's Liz? - Who's Liz?
她是学霸女神 是我的同校同学
She's the best. She's awesome. She's just a girl who goes to my school.
我真的很想告诉她 但是又感觉很奇葩 你懂吗？
And, yeah. I really wanna tell her, but it's kinda weird. You know?
- "嘿 我是蜘蛛侠" - 这有什么奇葩的？
- "Hey. I'm Spider-Man." - What's weird about that?
如果她期待的蜘蛛侠是像托尼・史塔克那样的呢？你想想 她看到是我会有多失望
What if she's expecting someone like Tony Stark? Imagine how disappointed she'd be when she sees me.
好吧 如果我是她 我一点都不会失望
Well, if I were her, I wouldn't be disappointed at all.
谢谢 凯伦 有个人能聊聊天的感觉真好
Thanks, KAREN. It's really nice to have somebody to talk to.
- 我们在这儿待了多久了？ - 37分钟
- Hey, how long have we been here, anyway? - 37 minutes.
什么？才37分钟？这太扯了！
What? 37 minutes? That's insane!
我受不了了 我要离开这儿
I cannot take this anymore. I gotta get out of here.
这里肯定有什么能用得上的
There's gotta be something in here I can use.
让我看看
Okay, let's see.
不行
Nope.
这个牛 嘿 这个看起来很像那个发光物
That's awesome. Hey, it's like the glowy thing.
这个发光物是一个易爆的奇塔瑞能量核
That glowy thing is an explosive Chitauri energy core.
- 什么 你是说我们一直随身带着一个炸弹？ - 它需要接受辐射才能激活爆炸
- Whoa, you mean we've been carrying around a bomb? - It would require radiation to transform it into an explosive state.
不不不不
No, no, no, no!
来人啊 快放我出去！
Hey, please! Please! Somebody let me out! Hey!
凯伦 你必须帮我覆写那个时间锁
KAREN you have to help me override that timelock!
- 好的凯伦 尝试低压运行 - 试验失败
- Okay, KAREN, lower the voltage and run it. - Trial unsuccessful.
好吧 我们要尝试每一个序列
Okay, we're just gonna have to try every sequence.
奈德 彼得 我们要迟到了 快点 我们走
Ned, Peter, we're gonna be late. Come on. Let's go.
好的 等下 马上就来
Okay. Hold on, hold on.
进行第247次尝试
Initiating trial 247.
成功了！成功了！
It worked! It works!
请确保所有手机已关机
Please be sure all cellphones are turned off.
凯伦 快带我回去十项全能比赛 越快越好
KAREN, you have to get me to the decathlon as fast as possible!
- 没问题 告诉我地点 - 就在华盛顿纪念碑对面
- Sure thing. Just tell me where it is. - It's right across the street from the Washington Monument.
- 这里是奈德的语音信箱 听到请留言 - 奈德 快回电话！那个发光物是炸弹！
- Hey, it's Ned. Leave a message. - Ned, call me back! The glowy thing's a bomb!
你右边有辆顺风车正在接近
There's a vehicle approaching on your right.
我们已经进入了决胜局
We have now entered sudden death.
下一题将决定冠军归属
The next correct answer wins the championship.
- 中心高中？ - 0
- Midtown Tech? - Zero.
回答正确 中心高中赢得了本次比赛的冠军！
That is correct. Midtown takes the championship!
- 我们赢了！ - 各位 我为你们感到骄傲
- We won! - Guys, I'm so proud of you!
跟你们说过 不需要彼得也能赢
Told you we don't need Peter.
闪电 你一个问题都没有回答
Flash, you didn't answer a single question.
米歇尔 你要拿着书进去参观么？
Taking it all in, Michelle?
啊 我只是觉得一个出自奴隶之手的东西没什么好庆祝的
Oh, yeah, I just umm, I don't really wanna celebrate something that was built by slaves.
噢 我确定华盛顿纪念碑不是由...
Oh, I'm sure the Washington Monument wasn't built by...
好吧 好好看书吧
Okay. Enjoy your book.
谢谢
Thanks.
- 奈德 你还活着！ - 彼得 你还好吗？
- Oh, Ned. You're alive! - Peter, are you okay?
- 奈德 那个发光物在哪？ - 别担心 它很安全 就在我背包里
- Ned, Ned, where's the glowy thing? - Don't worry. It's safe. It's in my backpack.
不是的 奈德 听好了 那个发光物非常危险
No, Ned! Listen! No, Ned! The glowy thing is dangerous!
你缺席了十项全能比赛 我帮你打掩护了
You missed the decathlon. I covered for you...
- 奈德 听我说！ - 我们在华盛顿纪念碑 你要怎么...
- Ned, listen to me! - We're in the Washington Monument. How're you gonna...
- 彼得 是你吗？ - 噢 嗨 丽兹
- Peter, is that you? - Oh, hey, Liz!
- 是丽兹吗？ - 请让奈德接电话
- Is that Liz? - Please put Ned back on the phone.
- 你应该告诉她你的想法 - 说真的 你应该庆幸我们赢了
- You should tell her how you feel. - Seriously, you are so lucky we won!
我很想发火 但我真的很担心你 你最近是怎么了？
You know, I wanna be mad, but I'm real worried. Like, what is going on with you?
- 丽兹 我必须和奈德说话 非常重要的事！ - 女士 请把所有物品都放在传送带上
- Liz, I have to talk to Ned, it's really important! - Miss, all items on the belt, please.
丽兹 奈德的背包里有非常危险的东西 不要让它通过X光扫描仪
Liz, there's something in his backpack that is really dangerous. Don't let it go through an x-ray.
丽兹？丽兹？糟了
Liz? Liz? Dammit!
哈灵顿先生 能不能由我来告诉彼得他被开除了
Hey Mr. Harrington, can I be the one to tell Peter he's expelled?
华盛顿纪念碑有555英尺5.125英寸高
The Washington Monument is 555 feet, 5 and one eighth inches tall.
由大理石和花岗岩堆砌而成
(), () , marble and granite are cut around the stone.
不不不 凯伦 上面发生了什么？
No, no, no, no! KAREN, what's going on up there?
奇塔瑞能量核被引爆了并且对电梯造成了严重的结构损坏
The Chitauri core has detonated and caused severe structural damage to the elevator.
- 我的朋友在上面 - 什么？
- My friends are up there. - What?!
啊 别担心女士 不会有事的
Uh, don't worry, ma'am. Everything's gonna be okay.
让一下 让一下 不是吧 这么高！
Excuse me, excuse me! Oh my God, that's tall!
- 我的天啊 快看天花板 - 大家请保持冷静
- Oh, my God. Look at the ceiling. - Just stay calm everyone.
我们要死在这里了
We are going to die here.
预计10分钟后发生灾难性事故
Estimating 10 minutes before catastrophic failure.
- 我们完蛋了 - 好了 各位 我知道这看上去很可怕
- We're freaking screwed. - Okay, guys, I know that looks scary,
但我们的安全系统还在运行
but our safety systems are working.
安全系统已经彻底失灵
The safety systems are completely failing.
- 我们在这里会很安全 - 电梯里的人正面临生命危险
- We're very safe in here. - The occupants are in imminent mortal danger.
我已经尽可能快了
I'm going as fast as I can!
预计125秒后发生灾难性事故
You now have 125 seconds until catastrophic failure.
- 什么？为什么？ - 预料之外的运动导致形势恶化
- What? Why? - Unexpected motion has caused the deterioration to escalate.
- 我该怎么进去？ - 激活侦察无人机
- How do I get in there? - Activating Reconnaissance Drone.
哇哦 这东西一直都在这里吗？太酷炫了！
Whoa. Has that been there this whole time? That's awesome!
寻找最佳入口点
Locating optimal entry point.
- 前往西南窗口 - 我这就去
- Proceed to southwest window. - KAREN I'm on my way.
天啊天啊 好吧
Oh, God. Oh, God. Okay.
怎么了？你已经到了西南窗口
What's wrong? You've reached the southwest window.
- 为什么犹豫了？ - 从来没来过这么高的地方
- Why are you hesitating? - It's just I've never been this high before.
你没有重新装置降落伞
You have also not reinstalled your parachute,
从这个高度跌落是致命的
so a fall from this height would most likely be lethal.
好吧
Alright.
- 怎么踢不碎？ - 这是四英寸厚的防弹玻璃
- Why is it not breaking? - It's 4 inch ballistic glass.
你需要更强的力量
You'll have to create more momentum.
我们是大都会警察 请亮明身份
This is DC metro police. Identify yourself.
我的朋友在里面！快停下！
My friends are in there! Stop!
请立刻回到地面！
Return to the ground! Immediately!
- 好了 谁是下一个 - 我！该我了！
- Okay, who's next? - Me! It's my turn!
闪电 你在干嘛？
Flash, seriously? What are you doing?
别管奖杯了！
Don't worry about the trophy!
退后！马上回到地面！
Stand down! Return to the ground immediately!
回到地面 否则我们开火了
Return to the ground, or we will open fire!
- 往上 往上 - 我能行的
- Go up, go up! - I got this.
拿好我的奖杯
Take my trophy.
这是你最后的机会
This is your last chance.
我感觉要死了
I'm gonna die.
我做到了！
I did it!
嗨 大家怎么样 别担心 我能搞定
Hey, how you doing? Don't worry about it, I got you.
太好了！太好了！
Yes! Yes!
- 嘿嘿嘿嘿！大胖子 别乱动 - 不好意思 不好意思
- Hey, hey, hey! Big guy, quit moving around! - I'm sorry, sir! So sorry.
- 你可以出去了 - 好的
- You can go. - Okay.
好了 该你了 快快快
All right. This is your stop. Go, go, go.
所有人都出去 快出去
Everybody out. Move it people. Move it.
丽兹！
Liz!
你没事的 你没事的
You're okay. You're okay.
- 好了 - 很好 继续 继续
- Okay. - Good. Come on up, come on.
- 各位靠后点 - 我抓住你了
- Guys, stand back. - I got you.
大家都没事吧？
So, is everyone okay?
彼得 你的机会来了
This is your chance, Peter.
此处致敬2002版蜘蛛侠经典镜头：倒挂蜘蛛吻
吻她
Kiss her.
谢谢你
Thank you.
你真的是彼得・帕克的朋友吗？
Are you really friends with Peter Parker?
我能完成下笔订单
I can finish the next order,
但如果没有了卡车上的新材料的话...
but without any new materials from that truck...
该死的
Dammit...
我们至少还能继续做加根的那笔交易吧？
We're still enough to do the Gargan deal though, right?
对 不过就到此为止了
Yeah. But then, that's it.
也许是时候完成那个高空密封装置了
Maybe it's time that I build the high altitude seal.
- 不要再提那个了 - 可是 差一点...
- Would you shut up about that? - Look, one job...
不行
No.
8年了 联调局没找上门
Eight years. Not a word from the feds.
史塔克大楼里的那帮万圣节装扮的复仇者们也没找上门
Nothing from those halloween costume- wearing bozos up there in Stark Tower.
然后突然就冒出来了一个穿着红色紧身裤的小混蛋...
And then all of a sudden, this little bastard in red tights shows up...
以为能摧毁我亲手建立起来的一切
And he thinks he can tear down everything I built.
可能么？
Really?
- 我得找到他 然后杀了他 - 找到他了
- I'm gonna kill him. I'm gonna find him... - Found him.
蜘蛛侠突然出现 拯救了一只来自皇后区的学术十项全能比赛队伍
The Spider-Man swooped in, heroically saving an academic decathlon team from Queens.
蒙面英雄的身份仍未揭开
The identity of the masked hero is still unknown.
妈妈！
Mom!
彼得 快过来！
Peter. Come here!
中心高中的学术十项全能队伍上周末击败了全国最强
This past weekend, Midtown's academic decathlon team defeated the country's best
赢得了全国冠军 在这之后又击败了死神
to win the national championship. Later that day, they also defeated death.
各种爆炸 萨莉在叫 闪电在叫 所有人都在叫
Explosives! Sally screamed! Flash screamed, everybody screaming!
到处都是紫色的激光和烟雾 大家挤作一团就像邦乔维的演唱会一样
There were purple lasers and smoke everywhere. It was (beep) tight. Just like a Bon Jovi concert.
没错 我们活下来了 这才是最重要的
As you know, we made it out alive. And that's the important thing.
我无法忍受在学校旅行中失去任何一名学生
I couldn't bear to lose a student on a school trip.
- 再也不要了- 谢天谢地 没有人
- Not again. - Thankfully, no one was seriously injured.
- 这都多亏了蜘蛛侠 - 谢谢你 蜘蛛侠
- Thanks to the Spider-Man. - Thank you, Spider-Man.
下一条：蜘蛛侠热潮正在席卷校园
Up next: The Spider-Man mania is sweeping the school.
你会如何展现你的蜘蛛精神？
How can you show your Spider spirit?
哥们儿 哥们儿
Dude, dude, dude...
名声大噪又无人知晓你的真实身份 你感觉如何？
What is it like being famous when nobody knows it's you?
- 太爽了 奈德 - 太爽了
- Crazy, Ned. - It is crazy!
- 我们应该告诉大家是你吗？ - 不
- Should we tell everyone? - No.
- 我应该告诉大家是你吗？ - 不 哥们儿 这不是个好主意
- Should I tell everyone? - No, dude. That's not a good idea.
- 好了 我们得去上课了 - 我不去上课
- Okay. Well, we're gonna go to class. - I'm not going to class.
- 你因为缺席十项全能比赛已经惹了很多麻烦了... - 哥们儿 听着 我已经搞清楚了
- But you're already in so much trouble for ditching the decathlon... - Dude, listen, I figured it out, right...
那个翅膀男正在偷灾害控制部门的材料
The wing suit guy is stealing from Damage Control.
用来制造武器 我现在只要抓到他就行了
And what he takes from Damage Control, that's how he builds the weapons. All I gotta do is catch him!
- 但是我们还有一个西班牙语测试 - 奈德 我很可能不会再回来上课了
- But we have a Spanish quiz. - Ned, I'm probably never gonna come back here.
史塔克先生把复仇者基地搬到纽约北部了 所以...
Mr. Stark is moving the Avengers upstate, so...
- 如果我带着这个翅膀男过去... - 伙计！
- when I bring this guy in... - Dude!
你要退学么？
You wanna be a high school dropout?
我已经不止是一名高中生了
I am so far beyond high school right now.
帕克！来我办公室一趟
Parker! My office.
那么 你被留堂了 你搞砸了
So. You got detention. You screwed up.
你知道你错了 问题是 你该怎么弥补？
You know what you did was wrong. The question is, how are you gonna make things right?
你可能想变得很酷
Maybe you were trying to be cool.
但是听听我这个被冷冻了65年的老家伙的建议吧
But take it from a guy who's been frozen for 65 years.
想要变酷的唯一方法就是遵守规矩
The only way to really be cool, is to follow the rules.
我们都知道什么是对的什么是错的
We all know what's right. We all know what's wrong.
下次再有蠢货想教唆你去...
Next time those turkeys try to convince you that something you know...
你去哪儿？回来！
Hey, where are you going? Get back here!
美国队长会怎么做？
What would Captain America do?
你怎么在这儿？你又没有被留校
Why are you here? You don't even have detention.
哦 我知道 我就是在这素描危机人物的画像
Oh, I know. I just like coming here to sketch people in crisis.
这个是你
It's you.
所以你的身体在发生变化 相信我 我知道那是什么感觉
So your body's changing. Believe me, I know how that feels.
梅？
May?
- 嗨 凯伦 你在吗？ - 嗨 彼得 你的西班牙语测试怎么样了？
- Hey, KAREN, what's up? - Hey, Peter. How was your Spanish quiz?
那个 我想你或许可以帮我 我想知道
Listen, I was wondering if you could help me. I'm trying to figure out who the guys...
那天晚上桥下的那些家伙是谁 我只记住了部分车牌号
under the bridge were that night, but, I mean I can only kinda remember part of the license plate.
我可以对那段录像进行面部识别
I can run facial recognition on the footage of that encounter.
- 录像？ - 是的 彼得
- Footage? - Yes, Peter.
- 我可以记录你看到的一切 - 所有事？
- I record everything you see. - Everything?
- 是的 - 每时每刻都记录了吗？
- Everything. - Like, all the time?
- 它叫做婴儿监护协议 - 好吧 当然了
- It's called the Baby Monitor Protocol. - Yeah, of course, it is.
- 嗯 看一下上周五的录像 - 没问题
- Yeah, just roll it back to last Friday. - With pleasure.
嗨 大家好 很不错的聚会
Hey, everyone! Yeah, kick- ass party. Hey, what's up, Liz?
你好啊 丽兹 彼得经常跟我提起你
Peter told me a lot about you.
不不 这只是我在瞎胡闹而已 播放那天晚些时候的...
No, this is just me messing around. Go later in the day.
- 这就是我 索尔 奥丁之子！ - 不不不 这显然不是我们想看的
- It is I, Thor, son of Odin! - No, no, no. That's definitely not what we wanna watch.
- 你真是非常有趣 - 快进到武器交易的时候
- Your impressions are very funny. - Fast forward to the arms deal.
好了 右边的两个是谁？
Okay. The two on the right, who are they?
正在搜索执法机构数据库...
Searching law enforcement databases...
- 没有找到这两个人的任何记录 - 没有？
- No records found for two of the individuals. - Nothing?
已识别一人 安龙・戴维斯 33岁
One individual identified. Aaron Davis, age 33.
- 有前科 并且就住在皇后区 - 那我们去拜访一下他吧
- He has a criminal record. And an address here in Queens. - Let's pay him a visit.
你想要激活增强性审讯模式吗？
Would you like me to activate the Enhanced Interrogation Protocol?
好啊
Yeah.
还记得我吗？
Remember me?
我要问你一些话 你要马上回答我
I need information and you're gonna give it to me now!
- 好吧 冷静... - 快点！
- Alright, chill... - Come on!
- 你的声音怎么了？ - 什么意思？我的声音怎么了？
- What happened to your voice? - What do you mean, what happened to my voice?
那天在桥下我听过你的声音 很像个女孩
I heard you by the bridge. I know what a girl sound like.
我不是女孩！我是男孩！我是说 我是个男人
I'm not a girl! I'm a boy! I mean, I'm a man.
- 我不管你是男孩还是女孩... - 我不是女孩！我是个男人
- I don't care what you are. Boy, girl... - I'm not a girl! I'm a man.
快告诉我是谁在出售那些武器？
Come on, man. Look, who is selling these weapons?
给我提供些名字 或者其他信息
I need to know. Give me names, or else.
你第一次干这事儿吧？
You ain't ever done this before, huh?
关闭增强性审讯模式
Deactivate interrogation mode.
哥们 那些人出售的武器非常危险
Look man, these guys are selling weapons that are crazy dangerous.
不能让他们这么逍遥法外
They can't just be out on the streets.
如果一个武器就能把德尔马先生的店切成两半..
Look, if one of them can just cut Delmar's bodega in half...
- 你知道德尔马？ - 对啊 皇后区最好的三明治
- You know Delmar's? - Yeah. The best sandwich in Queens.
- 天堂街的更好 - 啊 就是面包太多了点
- The subhaven's pretty good. - Nah, it's too much bread.
- 我喜欢面包 - 哥们 求你了
- I like bread. - Come on, man. Please.
白痴一样的审讯模式 凯伦 以后别再激活了
Stupid interrogation mode. KAREN, don't ever do that again.
那天晚上你对那家伙说"要开枪就冲我来"
The other night, you told that dude "if you're gonna shoot somebody, shoot me."
真的挺有种的
That's pretty ballsy.
我也不想那些武器出现在皇后区 我外甥也住在这儿
I don't want those weapons in this neighborhood. I got a nephew who live here.
那些人是谁？你有关于翅膀男的消息吗？
Who are these guys? What can you tell me about the guy with the wings?
只知道他是一个疯子 穿着像恶魔一样 除此以外 就没了
Other than he's a psychopath dressed like a demon? Nothing.
我不知道他是谁也不知道他在哪
I don't know who he is, or where he is.
但我知道他会去哪儿
I do know where he's gonna be.
- 真的吗？ - 对 我以前和一个很疯狂的家伙合作过
- Really? - Yeah, this crazy dude I used to work with. He's...
- 他应该在和翅膀男做交易 - 好的 太棒了！
- He's supposed to be doing a deal with him. - Yes! Yeah!
嘿 我都没有告诉你在哪 你怎么去
Hey. I didn't tell you where. You don't have a location.
对 就是 我的错 我犯傻了
Right. Of course. Yeah. My bad. Silly. Just... Yeah.
他在哪？
Where is it?
我能给你点建议吗？你这方面的工作有待加强
Can I give you some advice? You gotta get better at this part of the job.
不懂你的意思 我已经很有威慑力了
I don't understand. I'm intimidating.
- 斯塔腾岛渡口 11点 - 哦 那很快了
- The Staten Island Ferry. 11:00. - Oh, that's soon.
那个两小时后就自动溶解了
Hey that's gonna dissolve in two hours.
不不不 帮我解开
No, no, no, no. Come fix this.
- 两小时 你罪有应得 - 我还有冰激凌要吃呢 伙计
- Two hours. You deserve that. - I got ice cream here, man.
你是个罪犯 你罪有应得 再见了 罪犯先生
You deserve that, you're a criminal. Bye, Mr. Criminal!
漂亮
Nice.
凯伦 激活增强性侦查模式
Okay, KAREN. Activate Enhanced Reconnaissance mode.
- 没问题 - 他就在前面 主甲板
- Sure thing. - He's out front. Main deck.
- 我讨厌这家伙 - 这就是桥下的那个对吗？
- I hate this guy. - That's the guy from the bridge, right?
- 另一个是谁？ - 继续保持联络
- Who's that other guy? - Just keep me posted.
犯罪数据库中没有任何关于他的记录
There's no record of him in my criminal database.
有一通来自梅・帕克的电话 需要我转接到你的显示器上吗？
Incoming call from May Parker. Shall I reroute to your heads-up display?
现在没法接 我待会儿再打给她
I can't talk right now. I'll call her back.
小蜘蛛 帮我盯着那家伙
Hey, Droney. Keep an eye on that guy.
这回不能放跑任何人了
We can't let anybody get away this time.
- 左边的人是谁？ - 麦克・加根
- Who's the guy on the left? - Mac Gargan.
前科累累的杀人犯
Extensive criminal record including homicide.
是否需要激活一击必杀功能？
Would you like me to activate Instant Kill?
不 凯伦 别再提什么一击必杀了
No, KAREN. Stop it with the Instant Kill already!
白色小货车
White pick-up truck.
小蜘蛛 扫描整艘船 找到那辆白色小火车
Droney, scan the ship for a white pick-up truck.
太好了 武器买家卖家都齐了
This is too perfect. They got the weapons, the buyers, and the sellers all in one place.
托尼・史塔克来电
Incoming call from Tony Stark.
- 不不不 不接- 帕克先生
- No, no, no. Don't answer! - Mr. Parker.
- 有时间吗？- 我在学校呢-
- Got a sec? - Uhh, I'm actually at school.
- 你没在学校- 华盛顿的事干得漂亮啊......
- No, you're not. - Nice work in DC...
我老爸从来没有给我很多帮助  我现在要打破这个恶性循环...
My Dad never really gave me a lot of support. Now I'm just trying to break the cycle of chain...
- 我现在有点忙......- 我夸你的时候你不要打断我-
- I'm kind of in the middle of something right now... - Don't cut me off when I'm complimenting you.
总之 好事要发生了...那是什么声音？
Anyway. Great things are about to happen... What is that?
我在乐队训练...
I'm at band practice?
奇怪 哈皮跟我说你6周前就退出乐队了
That's odd. Happy told me you quit band six weeks ago.
- 怎么了？- 我要走了 结束通话！-
- What's up? - I got to go. End call!
这个归我了！
I'll take those!
喂 各位 非法武器交易渡船是10:30那班
Hey guys. The illegal weapons deal ferry was at 10:30.
你们错过了
You missed it.
那个蜘蛛人在这
Spider-guy's here.
喂喂喂  别那么着急
Whoa, whoa, whoa, not so fast.
你们还好吧？我错了 太用力了
Are you guys okay? My bad. That was a little hard.
要我说 之前另一个人更擅长用这武器
I gotta say, the other guy was way better with that thing.
说实话 把我吓到了
And honestly, I'm--- I'm shocked.
别动！FBI！趴在地上！
Freeze! FBI! Get on the ground!
- 什么？FBI？- FBI就是联邦调查局...
- Wait, what do you mean, FBI? - The FBI is the Federal Bureau of Investigation...
我知道FBI是什么 但是他们来这里干嘛？
I know what the FBI means, but what are they doing here?
快让开！快让开！
Get outta the way! Get outta the way!
小心 小心！快闪开！快闪开！快闪开！
Look out, look out! Move, move, move!
去顶层夹板 我们离开这里
Get to the top deck. We're getting out of here.
激活脉冲蛛网
Activate taser web!
你都不明白你在瞎搞什么
You're messing with things you don't understand.
我的天啊！我该怎么办？
Oh, my God! What do I do?
卡伦 帮我扫描船上的所有承重点
KAREN, give me an x-ray of the boat and target all the strongest points.
蛛网手榴弹！蛛网手榴弹！
Web grenade. Web grenade!
分散网
Stutter web.
干得好 彼得.你完成了98%- 98？
- Great job, Peter. You're 98% successful. - 98?
干得好 蜘蛛侠！
Yeah, Spider-Man!
不不不
No, no!
不！
No!
怎么回事？
What the hell?
你好 蜘蛛侠..."乐队训练" 是不是？
Hi, Spider-Man! "Band practice", was it?
此为钢铁侠新战甲：Mark 47
干得好 钢铁侠！
Yeah, Iron Man!
史塔克先生？ 史塔克先生 我能做点什么？
Uhh, Mr. Stark? Hey, Mr. Stark, can I do anything?
你想让我做些什么？
What do you want me to do?
我觉得你已经做得够多了
I think you've done enough.
就这样了？你要跑路了？
So that's it? You're just gonna run?
FBI的人盯上我们了
Feds were waiting for us.
现在 钢铁侠也盯上我们了
And now, we're on Iron Man's radar?
是啊 我要跑路了
Yeah, I'm running.
- 你也应该跑路了- 你知道我不能这么一走了之-
- You should, too. - You know I can't do that.
- 那现在怎么办？- 梅森
- So now, what? - Mason.
你的那个高海拔真空密封的玩意 能及时做出来吗？
Can you get that high altitude seal up and running in time?
确定么？可以
Seriously? Yes.
你绝对不会后悔的
You will not regret this.
你加入吗？
You in?
你上次搞砸的时候 我以为我能袖手旁观
Previously on "Peter screws the Pooch," I thought you'd stayed away from this,
事实上 这装备服价值百万美金 你为了掩盖行踪 黑入它的系统
instead, you hacked a multi-million dollar suit so you could sneak around,
背着我 做那些我让你别做的事
behind my back, doing the one thing I told you not to do.
- 大家都没事吧？- 都是你干的好事
- Is everyone okay? - No thanks to you.
都是我干的好事？
No thanks to me?
有人在外面贩卖那些武器 我一直跟你讲 你就是不听
Those weapons were out there and I tried to tell you about it, but you didn't listen.
你要是听我的 这些都不会发生
None of this would've happened if you had just listened to me.
你要是真的在乎 你本人就会来这
If you even cared, you'd actually be here.
我听了 小子 你以为是谁叫的FBI？
I did listen, kid. Who do you think called the FBI, huh?
你知不知道 我是唯一信任你的人
Do you know that I was the only one who believed in you?
其他人都说我真是疯了 居然招一个14岁的小孩
Everyone else said I was crazy to recruit a 14-year old kid.
- 我15了 - 闭嘴！大人在说话 别插嘴
- I'm 15. - No, this is where you zip it! All right? The adult is talking.
今晚要是有人死了怎么办？性质完全不同了 对吧？都是因为你
What if somebody had died tonight? Different story, right? 'Cause that's on you.
要是你死了 我就觉得是我的责任了
And if you died... I feel like that's on me.
- 我不想良心受谴责 - 是的 先生 对不起我...
- I don't need that on my conscience. - Yes, sir... I'm sorry, I...
- 对不起是没用的 - 我明白 我只是想要和你一样
- Sorry doesn't cut it. - I understand. I just wanted to be like you.
但我希望你能更好
And I wanted you to be better.
好吧 说这些都没用 我要把装备收回来
Okay. It's not working out. I'm gonna need the suit back.
- 收回多久？- 永远-
- For how long? - Forever.
不不不不 别...
No. No, no, no. Please...
- 给我吧 - 你不明白...
- Let's have it. - You don't understand...
- 我只有这套装备了 没了它我什么都不是-
This is all I have. I'm nothing without this suit.
- 如果没了它 你什么也不是 那你就不配有它 懂了吗？
If you're nothing without this suit, then you shouldn't have it.
美队在复联1中曾对钢铁侠有过类似质疑 后者已经证明了自己
天哪 我跟我爸当年的口气一模一样
Okay? God, I sound like my dad.
我没其他衣服了
I don't have any other clothes.
好 我们想办法解决
Okay. We'll sort that out.
我一整天都在打你电话
I've been calling you all day.
但你没接 你不能这样 然后又出了渡船的事...
But you don't answer your phone. You can't do that. Then this ferry thing happens...
我挺过了
纽约之行
我给5个警局打了电话
I've called five police stations.
5个 我给5个朋友打了电话 我给奈德的妈妈打了电话
Five. I called 5 of your friends. I called Ned's mother.
我没事 梅 我没事真的 放松点 我没事
I'm fine. May, I'm okay. Honestly, just relax. I'm fine.
少废话 我知道你留堂了
Cut the bullshit. I know you left detention.
我知道你在华盛顿的时候离开了酒店房间
I know you left the hotel room in Washington.
我知道你每晚都溜出房间 这一点都不好
I know you sneak out of this house every night. There's no fine.
彼得 你要告诉我到底怎么回事
Peter, you have to tell me what's going on.
说吧 我保证不说出去
Just lay it out. It's just me and you.
我失去了史塔克工业的实习机会
I lost the Stark internship.
- 什么？- 是的
- What? - Yeah.
怎么回事？
What happened?
我以为只要我努力工作 他就可以 他就会...
I just said that I could work really hard, and he could, he would, you know...
但是...,我搞砸了
But... I screwed it up.
没事 没事的
That's okay. It's okay.
没事...
It's okay.
不好意思让你担心了
I'm sorry I made you worry.
- 我知道我不想毁了你的生活- 是的 我知道-
- You know I'm not trying to ruin your life. - Yeah, I know.
- 我过去也溜出去过 - 啥？
- I used to sneak out, too. - Yeah?
去洗个澡你闻起来好像垃圾一样
And take a shower. You smell... Smell like garbage.
我知道
I know.
彼得 你是个好孩子 你是个聪明的孩子
Peter, you're a good kid, and you're a smart kid.
所以 保持头脑清醒 好不好？
So just try to keep your head straight, okay?
- 好 - 好吧 出去吧
- Okay. - Alright. Get out of here.
你被开除了吗？ 你要去46街的那个高中吗？
Are you expelled? Do you have to go to that high school on 46th,
- 那里的校长有一个十字弓 - 我很肯定那是传说 而且我还没被开除-
- where the principal has a crossbow? - Pretty sure that's an urban myth, but no, I'm not expelled.
你可真幸运啊
You're so lucky.
你好
- Hey. - Hey.
你好..我以为你在上微积分第五课
I thought you had Calculus, fifth period.
我刚在搞返校会的事
Yeah, I'm just dipped on Homecoming stuff.
嗯 听着 我...
Hey, look. I, uhh...
- 关于学术比赛的事 我想跟你道个歉- 没事啦
- I just wanted to apologize about the whole decathlon thing. - It's fine.
上周 学术比赛是最重要的事 但是...
Last week, decathlon was the most important thing, but...
我差点死了
I almost died.
不 我就是想说...
No. I ju--- I just mean that...
一点都不好 特别是...
It was not cool, especially be...
因为...
Because...
... 我喜欢你
... I like you.
我知道
I know.
- 你知道？- 你可真不会保密啊-
- You do? - You're terrible at keeping secrets.
是啊 你该很吃惊吧
Yeah, you'd be surprised.
我要去上课了 但是...
I, I gotta get to class, but, umm...
我们该出去玩一玩 但是我要被留校一会儿...
I'd say we should hang out, but I'm gonna be in detention for a bit...
但是...
Ever... But, umm...
我猜你已经有返校节的约会对象了
I guess you already have a date for Homecoming.
事实是 我一直忙着策划
Actually, I'm so busy planning it,
还没来得及想找约会对象 所以...
I never really got around to that part, so...
- 你想和我一起去吗？- 好呀-
- You wanna, go with me? - Yeah.
- 当然- 真的？
- Sure. - Really?
我的意思是...好啊 太好了
I mean, uhh... Great. Cool.
- 太好了- 我实际要走那边
- Cool. - I'm actually, going that way.
梅 我需要你的帮助！
May, I need your help!
怎么样
Right?
好戏登场 你有啥打算？
It's game day. So... What's the plan?
给她开车门 告诉她 她很漂亮
Open the door for her. Tell her she looks nice.
但是不能太夸张了 否则听起来很奇怪 还有...
But not too much because that's creepy. No. And, uhh...
和她跳舞的时候 我会把手放在她的屁股上
When I dance with her, I'll put my hands on her hips.
你的水仙花
Your daffodils.
- 爱你 - 拜拜
- Love you. - Bye.
- 你就是彼得吧 - 是的
- You must be Peter. - Yeah.
我是丽兹的爸爸
I'm Liz' Dad. Put her there.
手劲不小啊！进来 进来
Hell of a grip! Come on in here. Come on.
你好 彼得
Hi, Peter.
- 你看起来好帅啊- 谢谢
- You look very handsome. - Thank you.
你记住他的名字了吧？
You got his name, right?
- 弗莱迪？- 彼得
- Freddy? - Peter.
彼得  彼得
Peter. Peter.
- 我去叫丽兹 - 好
- I'm gonna go get Liz. - Okay.
- 你没事吧 彼得？- 没事
- You all right, Pete? - Yeah.
你看起来脸色很苍白啊
Because you look... pale.
你要喝点东西吗 比如波旁威士忌 苏格兰威士忌之类的？
You want something to drink, like a Bourbon, or Scotch, or something like that?
- 我还没到喝酒的年龄呢 - 回答正确
- I'm not old enough to drink. - That's the right answer.
哇 你看起来好美啊！
Wow! Wow, wow, wow, do you look beautiful.
- 老爸 不要让我出糗 - 她是不是很美 彼得？
- Please don't embarass me, Dad. - Doesn't she, Pete?
你看起来真不错
Yeah, you look really good.
再次回答正确
Once again, that's the right answer.
- 那是小花束吗？- 谢谢-
- Is that a corsage? - Thanks.
我是你们的司机 上车再弄那个花吧
Well, hey, I'm your chauffeur, so let's get this show on the road.
等下 我们要拍照 宝贝
No, no, no. We have to take some pictures, Babe.
在这 太好了...
Right here. Perfect. Okay...
来吧 彼得 靠近点
Come on, you guys. Peter, closer.
笑一个！
Smile!
拍好啦
There you go.
- 先生 你不用载我们去的 - 没事 没啥
- Sir, you don't have to drive us.. - Nah. It's not a big deal.
我要出城 顺路呢
I'm going out of town. It's right on my way.
- 他总是东奔西跑的 - 最后一次啦 宝贝
- He's always coming and going. - Last time, Babe.
- 谢谢 - 我保证
- Thank you. - I promise.
- 他挺不错的！- 嘘！
- He's cute! - Sst..!
- 过几天见 - 好
- See you in a couple of days. - Okay.
走吧 佩德罗
Come on, Pedro.
- 拜拜 彼得 玩得开心  - 好的 我会的
- Bye, Peter. Have fun. - Yeah, I will.
- 你打算做啥 彼得？- 什么？
- What are you gonna do, Pete? - What?
毕业后 你打算做啥？
When you graduate. What do you think you're gonna do?
- 嗯 我不知道  - 别拷问他啦 老爸
- Oh. Umm, I don't know - Don't grill him, Dad.
随便聊聊而已
Just sayin'. You know.
当你们上学的时候 肯定也规划好了自己的未来吧？
While you guys are going to that school, you pretty much have your life planned out, right?
我才高二
Yeah... No, I'm just a sophomore.
彼得在钢铁侠那里实习
Peter has an internship with Tony Stark, so,
- 我觉得他完全没必要担心  - 真的吗？
- I think he doesn't have to worry. - Really?
- 史塔克工业？ - 挺棒啊
- Stark? - So cool.
你在那具体做些什么呢？
What do you do?
事实上 我已经不在那里实习了
Yeah, actually, I don't intern for him anymore.
- 真的吗？- 实习有点...
- Seriously? - Yeah. It got, umm...
- 无聊了 - 无聊？
- Boring. - It was boring?
- 你还能见到蜘蛛侠呢 - 是么 蜘蛛侠？
- You got to hang out with Spider-Man. - Really? Spider-Man?
哇 他是个怎样的人？
Wow. What's he like?
他挺好的 挺好的人
Yeah, he's nice. Nice man.
实在人
Solid dude.
- 看！ 好可爱 - 哇
- Look! So cute. - Aww.
我以前见过你吧？
I've seen you around, right? I mean...
在哪里 我们见过...声音也有点熟悉...
Somewhere. We've, uhh... Have we ever? Because even the voice...
我想 可能是因为 他参加了学术比赛吧
He does academic decathlon, I think.
- 他参加过我的派对 - 非常不错的派对 真的不错！
- And he was at my party. - It was a great party! Really great, yeah.
房子很漂亮 很多窗户
Beautiful house. Lot of windows.
- 你就待了大概2分钟 - 我可待了不止2分钟
- You were there for like, 2 seconds. - That was... I was there longer than 2 seconds.
- 你消失了 - 没有啊 我没消失
- You disappeared. - No. No, I did not disappear.
有 你消失了 就像你经常一样消失 还有在华盛顿那次也是
Yes, you did, you disappeared like you always do. Like you did in DC, too.
华盛顿那件事可真恐怖啊
That was terrible, what happened down there in DC, though.
你害怕吗？
Were you scared?
你看到你的老朋友蜘蛛侠出现在电梯的时候 应该很高兴吧？
I bet you were glad when your old pal Spider-Man showed up in the elevator though, huh?
我实际上没有上去
Yeah, well, I... I actually didn't go up.
我一直在地面上看的
I saw it all from the ground.
他那天来救我们了 我们可真幸运
Pretty lucky that he was there that day.
蜘蛛侠干得不错
Good ol' Spider-Man.
老爸 绿灯啦
Dad. The light.
到啦
Here we are.
- 我们到啦 - 谢了 老爸-
- End of the line. - Thanks, Dad.
宝贝 你先进去 我和彼得聊点"私房话"
You head in there, Gumdrop. I'm gonna give Peter the, "Dad talk".
别被他吓到了
Don't let him intimidate you.
- 爱你  - 爱你 宝贝
- Love you. - Love you, Gumdrop.
开车小心哦
Have a safe flight.
你们真漂亮啊！
You guys look so pretty!
- 她知道吗？- 知道什么？
- Does she know? - Know what?
这么说来她不知道了 很好 保密工作做得不错
So she doesn't. Good. Close to the vest.
我很佩服你 我自己也有一些秘密
I admire that. I got a few secrets of my own.
我不想我女儿去约会也是有原因的...
Of all the reasons I didn't want my daughter to date...
彼得 没有什么比家庭更重要
Peter, nothing is more important than family.
你救了我女儿一命 我永远不会忘记
You saved my daughter's life and I could never forget something like that.
所以 我给你一次机会 你听好了
So I'm gonna give you one chance. Are you ready?
你走进去 然后忘记发生过的一切
You walk through those doors, you forget any of this happened.
然后永远...
And don't you ever, ever...
不要再干涉我的事
Interfere with my business again.
要是你再来的话...
Because if you do...
我会杀了你...
I'll kill you...
还有所有你爱的人
And everybody you love.
我会杀了你 这样做是为了保护我的家人 彼得
I'll kill you dead. That's what I I'll do to protect my family, Pete.
明白？
You understand?
喂 我刚刚放了你一马
Hey. I just saved your life.
- 现在 你该说些啥？- 谢谢
- Now, what do you say? - Thank you.
不用谢
You're welcome.
进去吧 好好陪我女儿
Now, you go in there, and you show my daughter a good time.
好吗？但也不要太过了
Okay? Just not too good.
他和你说啥了？
What did he say to you?
我得走了
I gotta go.
对不起 我不该这么对你的
I'm sorry. You don't deserve this.
他给了你机会 但是你却不珍惜
He gave you a choice. You chose wrong.
- 什么鬼？- 这是什么破衣服？
- What the hell? - What's with the crappy costume?
我的蛛网发射器
My web shooters.
一开始我还不确定这东西好不好用 但是...
I wasn't sure about this thing at first, but...
牛啊！
Damn!
真粗鲁！
Gross!
- 为什么他要派你过来？- 估计你永远都不会知道真相了
- Why did he send you here? - Guess you'll never know.
射得漂亮！
Nice shot!
奈德 那个有翅膀的人是丽兹的老爸
Ned, the guy with the wings is Liz' Dad.
- 什么？- 我必须要告诉史塔克先生-
- What? - I know. I gotta tell Mr. Stark.
联系哈皮・霍根 他是史塔克先生的安保主管
Call Happy Hogan. He's Mr. Stark's head of security.
找部电脑 然后追踪我的手机
And get a computer and track my phone for me.
- 你会没事吧？- 快点 我们要在他出城前抓住他！
- Are you gonna be okay? - Hurry, we gotta catch him before he leaves town!
那个晚餐真是抱歉 但是...
I'm sorry about dinner, but...
我知道新鲜的柠檬鲈鱼是啥样的 那个不新鲜 知道吗？
I know when Branzino's fresh. And that was not fresh, okay?
所以...
So...
闪电 我需要你的车和你的电话
Flash, I need your car and your phone.
先生 这车是我老爸的所以我不能给你...
Sir, technically this is my dad's car, sir. So I can't---
你好 奈德？喂喂喂 能听到我吗？- 我是奈德
- Hello, Ned? Hey, hey, hey. Can you hear me? - Go for Ned.
奈德 我需要你追踪我手机的位置
Ned. I need you to track my phone for me.
好 你的手机目前在哪？
Yeah, but where is it?
太机智了 他刚刚路过杰克逊大街
Genius move. Okay, he just passed a Gamestop on Jackson Avenue.
嘿 我在闪电的车上 这东西的前灯在哪里
Hey, where are the headlights on this thing? I'm in Flash's car.
- 我找找说明 - 好的 我开免提
- I'll pull the specs. - Okay, you're on speaker phone.
你偷了闪电的车？太牛了
You stole Flash's car? Awesome.
是啊 确实很牛！快让开 让开！
Yeah, it's awesome! Get outta the way, outta the way! Move!
- 彼得 你还好吧？- 我之前没有在路上开过车
- Peter, you okay? - I've never really driven before.
只在停车场练过 这可是巨大的进步啊！
Only in parking lots. This is a huge step up!
- 嘿 你联系上哈皮了没？- 我正在联系
- Hey, have you gotten through to Happy yet? - Yeah, I'm working on it.
我刚搞定了电话系统
I just gotta battle through the phone system.
幕后指挥！
Guy in the chair!
9分钟后起飞！哪位？
Takeoff in 9 minutes! Hello?
- 喂？哪位？- 哈皮先生 我是奈德
- Hello? Who is this? - Mr. Happy, it's Ned.
- 你是谁？- 我是彼得・帕克的助手
- Who? - I'm an associate of Peter Parker.
- 他有件很重要的事要告诉你...- 你在逗我吧
- He has something very important to tell you... - You gotta be shitting me.
- 该死！- 嘿 奈德 你查到怎么打开车前灯了吗？
- Damn! - Hey, Ned. How are we going on with those headlights?
旋转旋钮 转向方向盘的左边
Round knob, to the left of the steering wheel
- 顺时针转动- 往左么？好了
- turn it clockwise. - Left? Okay.
好了 完美 我的手机到哪里了？
Okay, perfect. So where's my phone now?
- 他停在了布鲁克林的一个旧工业园区 - 什么？没道理啊-
- He stopped in an old industrial park in Brooklyn. - What? That makes no sense.
- 我想他说要出城的 - 奇怪对了 我联系到哈皮先生了-
- I thought he said he was going out of town. - Weird. Oh, I reached Mr. Happy.
我觉得他不大喜欢你啊 而且 听起来他好像要搭飞机
Don't think he likes you, by the way. It sounded like he was catching a flight.
- 他说9分钟后起飞- 什么？
- He said something about taking off in 9 minutes. - What?
- 他周围都是箱子 - 箱子？
- He was surrounded by a bunch of boxes. - Boxes?
今天是搬家的日子！
It's moving day!
他要抢那架飞机！ 我要阻止他
He's gonna rob that plane! I gotta stop him.
好 还有8分钟起飞
All right. Wheels up in 8 minutes.
我们要装上钢铁侠的旧式反浩克盔甲
We just gotta load Tony's old Hulkbuster armor,
美国队长的新盾牌模型
prototype for Cap's new shield,
和魔法...魔法...
and the Megging... the Meg...
梅金吉奥德：北欧神话中索尔戴上后能让力量翻倍的腰带
雷神托尔的魔法腰带
Thor's magic belt.
好 慢点 你快到了 在你的右边
Okay, slow down. You're getting close. It's on your right.
- 什么？- 右转 右转！
- What? - Turn right. Turn right!
- 彼得！你还好吧？- 没事
- Peter! Are you okay? - Yeah.
你继续联系哈皮
Just keep trying to get through to Happy.
荣幸之至 蜘蛛侠
It's been an honor, Spider-Man.
你在这里干嘛？外面有舞会
What are you doing here? There's a dance.
我在看黄片
I'm... looking... at porn.
- 吃惊吧？- 嘿 彼得
- Surprised? - Oh, hey, Pete.
- 我没听见你进来了 - 结束了 我抓住你了
- I didn't hear you come in. - It's over. I've got you.
我知道 我要告诉你 彼得...
Y'know, I gotta tell you, Pete...
我真的真的欣赏你的勇气
I really, really admire your grit.
我知道为啥丽兹喜欢你了
I see why Liz likes you.
我确实知道了 你刚到我家的时候 我不大确定
I do. When you first came into the house, I wasn't sure.
我当时想 "就这小毛孩？"但是我现在明白了
I thought, "really?" But I get it now.
- 你怎么能这样对她？- 对她？
- How could you do this to her? - To her?
我没对她做什么 彼得我是"为了"她做这些事
I'm not doing anything to her, Pete. I'm doing this, for her.
嗯 没错
Hmm. Yeah.
彼得
Peter.
你太年轻了 你不理解这个世界怎么运作的
You're young. You don't understand how the world works.
没错 但是我知道把武器卖给罪犯是错的
Yeah, but I understand that selling weapons to criminals is wrong.
那你觉得 你的钢铁侠兄弟 为什么有钱买下那座大厦？
How do you think your buddy Stark paid for that tower?
还有他的那些小玩具？那些人 彼得 那些人高高在上 有钱有势...
Or any of his little toys? Those people, Pete, those people up there, the rich and powerful...
他们为所欲为 像我们这样的人...
They do whatever they want. Guys like us...
像你和我这样的普通人...
Like you and me...
他们不管我们死活 我们为他们铺路
They don't care about us. We build their roads,
我们给他们卖命 但是他们根本不在乎我们
and we fight all their wars and everything, but they don't care about us.
我们不得不去给他们收拾烂摊子 我们不得不去吃他们的残羹冷炙
We have to pick up after them. We have to eat their table scraps.
世界就是这么运作的
That's how it is.
我知道你知道我在说什么 彼得
I know you know what I'm talking about, Peter.
你跟我说这些干嘛？
Why are you telling me this?
因为我希望你能明白这些道理
Because I want you to understand.
而且..我需要点时间让它起飞
And... I needed a little time to get her airborne.
不好意思了 彼得
I'm sorry, Peter.
你在说什么啊？那玩意都没碰到我
What are you talking about? That thing hasn't even touched me yet.
确实但是还是得说...
True. But then again...
它根本就没打算碰到你
It wasn't really trying to.
- 老大 他们开始启动引擎了 快点- 好
- Chief, they're powering those engines. C'mon. - Okay.
好 好
Yeah. Yeah.
好的 准备好了吗？
Okay, ready?
有人吗？！
Hello?!
有人吗！！救命...
Hello?! Please...
嘿 救命...我被困住了！
Hey, please... I'm down here!
我在下面！我被卡住了 被卡住了！我动不了了...
I'm down here! I'm stuck. I'm stuck! I can't move...
我动不了...
I can't...
如果你没了装备什么都不是的话
If you're nothing without this suit,
你就不配有装备
then you shouldn't have it.
加油 彼得 加油 蜘蛛侠
Come on, Peter. Come on, Spider-Man.
加油 蜘蛛侠
Come on, Spider-Man.
加油 蜘蛛侠！
Come on, Spider-Man!
尝试拦截成功成功
Launch for intercept. Green light. Green light.
很好
Oh, yeah.
反射隐身板开启
Retro-reflective panels engaged.
检测到飞机了 但是感觉有些阻力
Got a visual on the plane, but feeling little resistance.
大概是因为那个新的涡轮机吧
It's probably just drag on the new turbines.
小心那些监控摄像头 待在盲区中
Look out for the cloaking camera. Stay on the blindspots.
噢 天哪
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
部署高空密封装置
Deploy high altitude vacuum seal.
这玩意最好管用 梅森
This better work, Mason.
相信我 老板只要拿到其中一个箱子 我们就发财了
Trust me, boss. Even one of those boxes, and we are set for life.
对啊
Yeah.
你有30秒进入驾驶舱关掉安全系统
You have 30 seconds to get to the cockpit and override their security.
- 复制应答器信号- 启动诱饵无人机
- Cloning transponder signal. - Launching decoy drone.
输入新坐标
Entering new coordinates.
- 很好 飞机还在航线上吧？- 是的 先生 在航线上
- Good. So it's on its way? - Yes, sir. Right on course.
好的 谢谢
Okay. Thank you.
好了
All right.
全是宝贝
Hot dog.
真是个难忘的返校节...
Just a typical Homecoming...
在一架隐形机的外面...
on the outside of an invisible jet...
和我的女朋友的老爸斗
fighting my girlfriend's dad.
哦 天哪！
Oh, God!
这招居然管用！
I can't believe that worked!
老大 老大 飞机正在下坠 快离开那里！
Chief, Chief, you're losing altitude. Get outta there!
我才不会空手而归
I'm not going home empty-handed.
哦 天哪！
Oh, my God!
快离开那里！你在干嘛？
Get out of there! What are you doing?!
快转弯 快转弯！
Please turn, please turn!
嘿 佩德罗
Hey, Pedro.
找到了
Bingo.
你的翅膀...你的翅膀要爆炸啦！
Your wings... Your wings are gonna explode!
- 回家吧 彼得！- 我在救你！
- Time to go home, Pete! - I'm trying to save you!
不！
No.
他就这样...
He was just like...
然后你就这样...
And you were like...
然后我就这样打了他...
And then I just hit him with the...
简直太...哦 我的天哪
It was so... Oh, my God.
- 你救了我- 太酷了
And you saved me. Awesome.
嘿 丽兹！
Hey, Liz!
我会想你的
I'm gonna miss you.
丽兹...
Liz.
丽兹 听着 我很抱歉
Liz, look, I'm so sorry.
你说过很多次了这次抱歉什么？
You say that a lot. What are you sorry for this time?
舞会吗？
The dance?
那事确实很过分
That, was a pretty crappy thing to do.
是的 但是...你老爸 很难想象 你经历了这么多事情
Yeah, but... Your Dad. I can't imagine what you're going through.
如果有什么我可以帮忙的...
If there's anything I can do to help...
我们要帮到俄勒冈去了
I guess we're moving to Oregon.
妈妈说那里不错 所以挺好的
Mom says it's nice there, so that's cool.
无论如何
Anyways,
我爸受审的时候不希望我们在这里 所以...
Dad doesn't want us here during the trial, so...
丽兹 我...我...
Liz, I... I...
再见 彼得
Bye, Peter.
无论发生什么 我希望你都能搞定
Whatever's going on with you, I hope you figure it out.
祝贺我们获得学术比赛全国冠军！
Congratulations, decathlon national champions!
我一会就得把它放回奖杯柜 但是
I'm gonna have to put this back in the trophy case soon, but,
为了在训练的时候激励大家
just for motivation right now, at this practice.
我就提前说了 明年我们需要一个新队长
I'm a little ahead of the game, but we will need a new team captain next year.
我提名米歇尔
So I am appointing Michelle.
谢谢 我朋友叫我"迈克尔・杰克逊"
Thank you. My friends call me "MJ."
我以为你没有朋友呢
I thought you didn't have any friends.
我确实没有
I didn't.
- 我得走了- 嘿 你去哪里？
- I gotta go. - Hey, where're you going?
你在隐瞒什么呢 彼得？
What are you hiding, Peter?
我开玩笑的 你不用告诉我 拜拜
I'm just kidding. I don't care. Bye.
好吧 我们应该练习下
Alright. So, we should run some drills.
嘿 哈皮 你在这里做什么？
Hey, Happy. What are you doing here?
我欠你个人情
I really owe you one.
我不知道没了这份工作咋办
I don't know what I would do without this job.
我是说 我认识钢铁侠以前...
I mean, before I met Tony...
你在这里呆了多久了？
So, how long have you been here?
呆到我都觉得尴尬了 老板要见你
Long enough to be awkward. Boss wants to see you.
他也在这里？
Is he here, too?
在厕所里？不 他在新的总部
In the toilet? No. He's upstate.
新的总部？你说的那个新复仇者基地？
Upstate? Like upstate, upstate?
是的 走吧
Yeah. Let's go.
看看四周 是不是看起来很不错？
Take a look. It's pretty impressive, huh?
这里刚刚完工
They just finished remodelling the whole thing.
- 你不是每天都能见到这个吧- 噢 你们来啦
- You don't see that everyday. - Oh, there they are.
- 路上顺利吧？- 很好
- How was the ride out? - Good.
我要和孩子单独谈谈
Give me a minute with the kid.
- 真的？- 是的
- Seriously? - Yeah.
- 我要和孩子谈谈- 我就在附近等着
- I gotta talk to the kid. - I'll be close behind.
走远点吧 走远一点比较好
How about a loose follow, alright? Boundaries are good.
彼得所穿T恤是钢铁侠3中小辣椒同款 图案为物理笑话 而非漫威漫画
不好意思 收回你的装备 你可以拿回去了
Sorry I took your suit. I mean, you had it coming.
其实 这么看来 我收回的时机很合适 爱之深责之切嘛 对吧？
Actually, it turns out, it was the perfect, sort of tough love moment that you needed, right?
驱使你继续努力 对吧？你觉得呢？
To urge you on, right? Wouldn't you think? Don't you think?
你回答"对"就行了
Let's just say it was.
- 史塔克先生 我真的...- 你当时确实搞砸了很多事
- Mr. Stark, I really... - You screwed the pooch hard, big-time.
但是后来 你做了正确的事
But then, you did the right thing.
打个比方 你把狗带到了免费的诊所 你...
You took the dog to the free clinic, you...
然后又养了混血小狗...好吧 这个比方不大恰当
Raised the hybrid puppies... All right, not my best analogy.
我之前看错你了
I was wrong about you.
我想 给你一些指导...
I think with a little more mentoring...
你会是团队里的得力干将
You could be a real asset to the team.
- 团队？- 是的 总之...
- To the team? - Yeah. Anyway...
这扇门后面有差不多50名记者
There's about 50 reporters behind that door.
真正的记者 不是那些开博客的
Real ones, not bloggers.
等你准备好...我想让你试下这个
When you're ready... I want you to try that on.
我要向世界宣布复仇者联盟最新成员
And I'll introduce the world to the newest official member of the Avengers:
蜘蛛侠
Spider-Man.
好好欣赏下吧
Yeah. Give that a lick.
发布会以后 哈皮会带你去你的房间 你的新住处
So, after the press conference, Happy will show you to your room, your new quarters.
- 他住哪间？他住幻视隔壁吧？- 嗯 幻视那间门不是很大
- Where's he between? He's next to Vision? - Yeah, Vision's not big on doors.
谢谢你 史塔克先生
Thank you, Mr. Stark.
但是 我...我挺好的
But, I... I'm good.
你挺好的？好 你怎么好了？
You're good? Good, how are you good?
我是说 我这段时间 宁愿脚踏实地
I mean, I'd rather just stay on the ground, for a little while.
做一个友善的 乐于帮助邻居的蜘蛛侠
Friendly, neighborhood Spider-Man.
总有些普通人需要帮助 对吧？
Somebody's gotta stick out for the little guy, right?
你要拒绝我么？你最好再考虑一下 看看那个装备
Are you turning me down? You better think about this. Look at that.
再看看我 最后问你一遍 留还是不留？
Look at me. Last chance: Yes or No?
- 不留 - 好
- No. - Okay.
布鲁斯・斯普林斯汀：美国著名摇滚歌手
就像斯普林斯汀一样 当个草根英雄 社会氛围就是这样啊
It's kind of a Springsteeny, working class hero, vibe of the day.
哈皮会送你回家
Happy will take you home.
- 对吧？- 是的
- Yeah? - Yeah.
你介意在车上等下吗？给我一会儿
You mind waiting in the car? I need a minute.
- 谢谢你 史塔克先生- 没事的 帕克先生 不客气
- Thank you, Mr. Stark. - Yes, Mr. Parker. You're very welcome.
再见了
See you around.
这是个测试吧？门后面没人吧？
That was a test, right? There's nobody back there?
对 你通过了 快走吧 小屁孩
Yes. You passed. All right, skedaddle there, young buck.
- 谢谢 史塔克先生 谢谢你！- 嗯 也谢谢你啦！
- Thank you, Mr. Stark. Thank you! - Yeah. Thank you!
跟你说过的 他是个不错的孩子
Told you he's a good kid.
- 那孩子呢？- 他走了
- Where's the kid? - He left.
- 他们都等着呢 - 其实 他做了一个很成熟的决定
- Everybody's waiting. - You know what, he actually made a really mature choice.
- 他刚刚让我们大吃一惊 - 你们是不是搞砸了？
- He just surprised the heck out of us. - Did you guys screw this up?
- 他让那小孩在车里等他 - 你在逗我吧？
- He told the kid to go wait in the car. - Are you kidding me?
那可有一屋子人 等着我们的重要声明
I have a room full of people in there, waiting for some big announcement.
- 那我要怎么解释？- 想想啊 要不...
- What am I gonna tell them? - Think of something. How about...
- 哈皮 你带了那个戒指吗？- 我...
- Happy, do you still got that ring? - Do I...
- 订婚戒指 - 这还用说 从2008年起 我就一直把它带在身边
- The engagement ring. - Are you kidding? I've been carrying this since 2008.
2008年即钢铁侠1公映的年份
- 很好 - 我觉得 我能想出比这个更好的主意
- Okay. - I think I can think of something better than that.
这能给我们争取些时间
Buy us a little time.
你这拖得也是够久了
Like we need time.
- 你居然一直随身带着这个戒指 简直难以置信 - 亲爱的 要不要我帮你开门？
- I can't believe you have that thing in your pocket. - Can I get the door for you, Hon?
嘿 梅 晚饭做好了吗？
Alright.
这是属于你的 ――钢铁侠
Hey, May, did you get dinner already?
梅？
May?
什么鬼！
What the fu---